<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
<array name="quotes">
<item>"My experience is that as soon as people are old enough to know better, they don't know anything at all."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"No woman should ever be quite accurate about her age. It looks so calculating."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"Well enough for old folks to rise early, because they have done so many mean things all their lives they can't sleep anyhow."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Old age comes on suddenly, and not gradually as is thought."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"We turn not older with years, but newer every day."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"When they tell me I'm too old to do something, I attempt it immediately."	Pablo Picasso</item>
<item>"You're never too old to become younger."	Mae West</item>
<item>"The older I grow the more I distrust the familiar doctrine that age brings wisdom."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"You know you're getting old when the candles cost more than the cake."	Bob Hope</item>
<item>"Middle age is when your age starts to show around your middle."	Bob Hope</item>	
<item>"There is still no cure for the common birthday."	John Glenn</item>	
<item>"It's not how old you are, it's how hard you work at it."	Jonah Barrington</item>
<item>"Aging is mandatory. Maturity is optional."	Chris Antonak</item>	
<item>"Anyone can get old, all you have to do is live long enough."	Groucho Marx</item>
<item>"Age is a very high price to pay for maturity."	Tom Stoppard</item>
<item>"And in the end, it's not the years in your life that count. It's the life in your years."	Abraham Lincoln</item>
<item>"Middle age is when you've met so many people that every new person you meet reminds you of someone else."	Ogden Nash</item>
<item>"He who is of calm and happy nature will hardly feel the pressure of age, but to him who is of an opposite disposition youth and age are equally a burden."	Plato</item>
<item>"My Grandmother is over eighty and still doesn't need glasses. Drinks right out of the bottle."	Henny Youngman</item>
<item>"The advice of their elders to young men is very apt to be as unreal as a list of the hundred best books."	Oliver Wendell Holmes</item>
<item>"America...just a nation of two hundred million used car salesmen with all the money we need to buy guns and no qualms about killing anybody else in the world who tries to make us uncomfortable."	Hunter S. Thompson</item>
<item>"You give me a credit to which I have no claim in calling me 'the writer of the Constitution of the United States.' This was not, like the fabled Goddess of Wisdom, the offspring of a single brain. It ought to be regarded as the work of many heads and many hands."	James Madison</item>
<item>"The Americans combine the notions of Christianity and of liberty so intimately in their minds, that it is impossible to make them conceive the one without the other."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"It was by the sober sense of our citizens that we were safely and steadily conducted from monarchy to republicanism, and it is by the same agency alone we can be kept from falling back."	Thomas Jefferson</item>
<item>"Let the word go forth from this time and place, to friend and foe alike, that the torch has been passed to a new generation of Americans."	John F. Kennedy</item>
<item>"My fellow citizens of the world: ask not what America will do for you, but what together we can do for the freedom of man."	John F. Kennedy</item>
<item>"Let every nation know, whether it wishes us well or ill, that we shall pay any price, bear any burden, meet any hardship, support any friend, oppose any foe, in order to assure the survival and the success of liberty."	John F. Kennedy</item>
<item>"To those new States whom we welcome to the ranks of the free, we pledge our word that one form of colonial control shall not have passed away merely to be replaced by a far more iron tyranny."	John F. Kennedy</item>
<item>"My dream is of a place and a time where America will once again be seen as the last best hope of earth."	Abraham Lincoln</item>
<item>"When you stand for your liberty, we will stand with you."	George W. Bush</item>
<item>"The survival of liberty in our land increasingly depends on the success of liberty in other lands."	George W. Bush</item>
<item>"The whole life of an American is passed like a game of chance, a revolutionary crisis, or a battle."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"Born often under another sky, placed in the middle of an always moving scene, himself driven by the irresistible torrent which draws all about him, the American has no time to tie himself to anything, he grows accustomed only to change, and ends by regarding it as the natural state of man. He feels the need of it, more he loves it; for the instability; instead of meaning disaster to him, seems to give birth only to miracles all about him."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"Americans are so enamored of equality, they would rather be equal in slavery than unequal in freedom."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"In America the majority raises formidable barriers around the liberty of opinion; within these barriers an author may write what he pleases, but woe to him if he goes beyond them."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"When American(s) ask for the cooperation of (their) fellow citizens, it is seldom refused; and I have often seen it afforded spontaneously and with great good will."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"The surface of American society is covered with a layer of democratic paint, but from time to time one can see the old aristocratic colours breaking through."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>	
<item>"In the United States the majority undertakes to supply a multitude of ready-made opinions for the use of individuals, who are thus relieved from the necessity of forming opinions of their own."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"There is hardly a political question in the United States which does not sooner or later turn into a judicial one."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"America is great because she is good. If America ceases to be good, America will cease to be great."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"It belongs to human nature to hate those you have injured."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"Any reviewer who expresses rage and loathing for a novel is preposterous. He or she is like a person who has put on full armor and attacked a hot fudge sundae."	Kurt Vonnegut</item>
<item>"Anger as soon as fed is dead. 'Tis starving makes it fat."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"I know of no more disagreeable situation than to be left feeling generally angry without anybody in particular to be angry at."	Frank Moore Colby</item>
<item>"Many people lose their tempers merely from seeing you keep yours."	Frank Moore Colby</item>
<item>"When angry count to four; when very angry, swear."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Anger is never without an argument, but seldom with a good one."	George Savile</item>
<item>"When you give a lesson in meanness to a critter or a person don't be surprised if they learn their lesson."	Will Rogers</item>
<item>"Look not back in anger, nor forward in fear, but around you in awareness."	Ross Hersey</item>
<item>"A man is measured by the size of things that anger him."	Geof Greenleaf</item>
<item>"When angry, count ten before you speak; if very angry, a hundred."	Thomas Jefferson</item>
<item>"Anger will never disappear so long as thoughts of resentment are cherished in the mind. Anger will disappear just as soon as thoughts of resentment are forgotten."	Siddhartha Buddha</item>
<item>"I was angry with my friend I told my wrath, my wrath did end. I was angry with my foe: I told it not, my wrath did grow."	William Blake</item>
<item>"The degree of one's emotions varies inversely with one's knowledge of the facts: the less you know the hotter you get."	Bertrand Russell</item>
<item>"I conquered my hostility by putting it away until the day I might need it."	Nachman of Bratslav</item>
<item>"An angry man is unfit to pray."	Nachman of Bratslav</item>
<item>"You can't shake hands with a clenched fist."	Indira Gandhi</item>
<item>"In time we hate that which we often fear."	William Shakespeare</item>
<item>"I keep my good health by having a very bad temper, kept under good control."	Theodore Roosevelt</item>
<item>"The greatest remedy for anger is delay."	Thomas Paine</item>
<item>"A door is what a dog is perpetually on the wrong side of."	Ogden Nash</item>
<item>"All animals are equal but some animals are more equal than others."	George Orwell</item>
<item>"A 'geek' by definition is someone who eats live animals....I've never eaten live animals."	Crispin Glover</item>
<item>"Women and cats will do as they please, and men and dogs should relax and get used to the idea."	Robert Heinlein</item>
<item>"Man [has] always assumed that he was more intelligent than dolphins because he had achieved so much-the wheel, New York, wars and so on-while all the dolphins had ever done was muck about in the water having a good time. But conversely, the dolphins had always believed that they were far more intelligent than man-for precisely the same reason."	Douglas Adams</item>
<item>"I believe that our Heavenly Father invented man because he was disappointed in the monkey."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"I have from an early age abjured the use of meat, and the time will come when men will look upon the murder of animals as they now look upon the murder of men."	Leonardo da Vinci</item>
<item>"Remember if you marry for beauty, thou bindest thyself all thy life for that which perchance, will neither last nor please thee one year: and when thou hast it, it will be to thee of no price at all."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"Beauty is not caused. It is."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"Beauty is a sign of intelligence."	Andy Warhol</item>
<item>"The flowers anew, returning seasons bring! But beauty faded has no second spring."	Frank Moore Colby</item>
<item>"I have always been offended by the song that says, 'Everything is beautiful in its own way.' If everything is beautiful, then the word 'beautiful' has no meaning. If everything were purple, there would be no word 'purple' in the language because it would not distinguish one thing from another."	Thomas Sowell</item>
<item>"In the Orthodox spiritual tradition, the ultimate moral question we ask is the following: Is what we are doing, is what I am doing, beautiful or not?"	Carolyn Gifford</item>
<item>"Beautiful young people are accidents of nature, But beautiful old people are works of art."	Eleanor Roosevelt</item>
<item>"It is better to be beautiful than to be good. But it is better to be good than to be ugly."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"The best and most beautiful things in the world cannot be seen or even touched. They must be felt with the heart."	Helen Keller</item>
<item>"Think of all the beauty that's still left in and around you, and be happy."	Anne Frank</item>
<item>"Calm, lasting beauty comes only in a dream, and this solace the world had thrown away when in its worship of the real it threw away the secrets of childhood and innocence."	H.P. Lovecraft</item>
<item>"Everything has beauty, but not everyone sees it."	Confucius</item>
<item>"It is hard, if not impossible, to snub a beautiful woman - they remain beautiful and the rebuke recoils."	Winston Churchill</item>
<item>"The criterion of true beauty is that it increases on examination; if false, that it lessens. There is therefore, something in true beauty that corresponds with right reason, and is not the mere creation of fancy."	Fulke Greville</item>
<item>"No; we have been as usual asking the wrong question. It does not matter a hoot what the mockingbird on the chimney is singing. The real and proper question is: Why is it beautiful?"	Annie Dillard</item>
<item>"There is no cosmetic for beauty like happiness."	Marguerite Gardiner Blessington</item>
<item>"Strange that the vanity which accompanies beauty -- excusable, perhaps, when there is such great beauty, or at any rate understandable -- should persist after the beauty was gone."	Mary Arnim</item>
<item>"Beauty is a short-lived tyranny."	Socrates</item>
<item>"Beauty is all very well at first sight; but whoever looks at it when it has been in the house three days?"	George Bernard Shaw</item>
<item>"We ascribe beauty to that which is simple; which has no superfluous parts; which exactly answers its end; which stands related to all things; which is the mean of many extremes."	Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
<item>"The object of teaching a child is to enable him to get along without a teacher."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"There are perhaps no days of our childhood we lived so fully as those we spent with a favorite book."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"If there is anything we wish to change in the child, we should first examine it and see whether it is not something that could better be changed in ourselves."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"Children are educated by what the grown-up is and not by his talk."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"Motherhood is a biological fact, while fatherhood is a social invention."	Margaret Mead</item>
<item>"Being born is like being kidnapped. And then sold into slavery."	Andy Warhol</item>
<item>"Ask your child what he wants for dinner only if he's buying."	Fran Lebowitz</item>
<item>"How is it that little children are so intelligent and men so stupid? It must be education that does it."	Alexandre Dumas</item>
<item>"All children are artists. The problem is how to remain an artist once he grows up."	Pablo Picasso</item>
<item>"A baby is God's opinion that life should go on."	Carl Sandburg</item>
<item>"Kids are cute, babies are cute, puppies are cute. The little things are cute. See, nature did this on purpose so that we would want to take care of our young. Made them cute. Tricked us. Then gradually they get older and older, until one day your mother sits you down and says, 'You know, I think you're ugly enough to get your own apartment.'"	Cathy Ladman</item>
<item>"There is no finer investment for any community than putting milk into babies."	Winston Churchill</item>
<item>"A baby is an inestimable blessing and bother."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Have children while your parents are still young enough to take care of them."	Rita Rudner</item>
<item>"Educate your children to self-control, to the habit of holding passion and prejudice and evil tendencies subject to an upright and reasoning will, and you have done much to abolish misery from their future and crimes from society."	Benjamin Franklin</item>
<item>"We each have the kind of children we deserve."	Nachman of Bratslav</item>
<item>"The man who disobeys his parents will have disobedient sons."	Nachman of Bratslav</item>
<item>"A strict master will not have understanding sons."	Nachman of Bratslav</item>
<item>"Providence protects children and idiots. I know because I have tested it."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Never worry about the size of your Christmas tree. In the eyes of children, they are all thirty feet tall."	Larry Wilde</item>
<item>"What I just said is the fundamental, end-all, final, not-subject-to-opinion absolute truth, depending on where you're standing."	Steve Martin</item>
<item>"If I could drop dead right now, I'd be the happiest man alive."	Samuel Goldwyn</item>
<item>"Outside of a dog, a book is a man's best friend. Inside of a dog, it is too dark to read."	Groucho Marx</item>
<item>"It is a mistake to think you can solve any major problems just with potatoes."	Douglas Adams</item>
<item>"Please, if you ever see me getting beaten up by the police, please put your video camera down and help me."	Bobcat Goldthwait</item>
<item>"Thou shall not kill. Thou shall not commit adultery. Don't eat pork. I'm sorry, what was that last one? Don't eat pork? Is that the word of God, or is that pigs trying to outsmart everybody?"	Jon Stewart</item>
<item>"If it looks like a duck, and quacks like a duck, we have at least to consider the possibility that we have a small aquatic bird of the family anatidae on our hands."	Douglas Adams</item>
<item>"Stand-up comedy is transient. History shows that you can stand up for so long; after that, you're asked to sit down."	Steve Martin</item>
<item>"Don't worry about the world coming to an end today. It's already tomorrow in Australia."	Charles Schulz</item>
<item>"I'm very proud of my gold pocket watch. My grandfather, on his deathbed, sold me this watch."	Woody Allen</item>
<item>"My Grandmother is over eighty and still doesn't need glasses. Drinks right out of the bottle."	Henny Youngman</item>
<item>"I told the doctor I broke my leg in two places. He told me to quit going to those places."	Henny Youngman</item>
<item>"I am so amazingly cool you could keep a side of meat in me for a month. I am so hip I have difficulty seeing over my pelvis."	Douglas Adams</item>
<item>"Nothing travels faster than the speed of light, with the possible exception of bad news, which obeys its own set of laws."	Douglas Adams</item>
<item>"Happiness is having a large, loving, caring, close-knit family in another city."	George Burns</item>
<item>"Those are my principles. If you don't like them I have others."	Groucho Marx</item>
<item>"I told my psychiatrist that everyone hates me. He said I was being ridiculous - everyone hasn't met me yet."	Rodney Dangerfield</item>
<item>"I just finished my first book. Pretty soon, I'm gonna read another."	Rodney Dangerfield</item>
<item>"I'm at an age where I think more about food than sex. Last week I put a mirror over my dining room table."	Rodney Dangerfield</item>
<item>"My grandmother started walking five miles a day when she was sixty. She's ninety-five now, and we don't know where the hell she is."	Ellen DeGeneres</item>
<item>"The Goliath of totalitarianism will be brought down by the David of the microchip."	Ronald Reagan</item>
<item>"Today, you always know whether you are on the Internet or on your PC's hard drive. Tomorrow, you will not care and may not even know."	Bill Gates</item>
<item>"The object of teaching a child is to enable him to get along without a teacher."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Everyone who is incapable of learning has taken to teaching."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"Men are born ignorant, not stupid; they are made stupid by education."	Bertrand Russell</item>
<item>"We are shut up in schools and college recitation rooms for ten or fifteen years, and come out at last with a bellyful of words and do not know a thing."	Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
<item>"An education isn't how much you have committed to memory, or even how much you know. It's being able to differentiate between what you know and what you don't."	Malcolm Forbes</item>
<item>"Education's purpose is to replace an empty mind with an open one."	Malcolm Forbes</item>
<item>"What sculpture is to a block of marble, education is to the soul."	Joseph Addison</item>
<item>"If I ran a school, I'd give the average grade to the ones who gave me all the right answers, for being good parrots. I'd give the top grades to those who made a lot of mistakes and told me about them, and then told me what they learned from them."	Buckminster Fuller</item>
<item>"The secret of education is respecting the pupil."	Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
<item>"We are faced with the paradoxical fact that education has become one of the chief obstacles to intelligence and freedom of thought."	Bertrand Russell</item>
<item>"The recipe for perpetual ignorance is: be satisfied with your opinions and content with your knowledge."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"The mind of the thoroughly well-informed man is a dreadful thing. It is like a bric-à-brac shop, all monsters and dust, with everything priced above its proper value."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"Life is not divided into semesters. You don't get summers off and very few employers are interested in helping you find yourself."	Bill Gates</item>
<item>"From kindergarten to graduation, I went to public schools, and I know that they are a key to being sure that every child has a chance to succeed and to rise in the world."	Dick Cheney</item>
<item>"It is the supreme art of the teacher to awaken joy in creative expression and knowledge."	Albert Einstein</item>
<item>"Beware of the man who works hard to learn something, learns it, and finds himself no wiser than before. He is full of murderous resentment of people who are ignorant without having come by their ignorance the hard way."	Kurt Vonnegut</item>
<item>"People will pay more to be entertained than educated."	Johnny Carson</item>
<item>"While the romanticized ideal of universal public education resonates with the cognoscenti who oppose vouchers, poor urban families just want the best education for their children, who will certainly need it to function in our high-tech and advanced society."	Clarence Thomas</item>
<item>"If a nation expects to be ignorant and free, in a state of civilization, it expects what never was and never will be."	Thomas Jefferson</item>
<item>"We are living in a world, where what we earn is a function of what we learn."	Bill Clinton</item>
<item>"When men are full of envy they disparage everything, whether it be good or bad."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"Such men as he be never at heart's ease whiles they behold a greater than themselves, and therefore are they very dangerous."	William Shakespeare</item>
<item>"I am Envy. I cannot read and therefore wish all books burned."	Christopher Marlowe</item>
<item>"Love looks through a telescope; envy, through a microscope."	Josh Billings</item>
<item>"Skepticism is the beginning of faith."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"Liberty cannot be established without morality, nor morality without faith."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"It is always more difficult to fight against faith than against knowledge."	Adolf Hitler</item>
<item>"Faith may be defined briefly as an illogical belief in the occurrence of the improbable."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"Duty, honour, country: Those three hallowed words reverently dictate what you ought to be, what you can be, what you will be. They are your rallying point to build courage when courage seems to fail, to regain faith when there seems to be little cause for faith, to create hope when hope becomes forlorn."	Douglas MacArthur</item>
<item>"Duty cannot exist without faith."	Benjamin Disraeli</item>
<item>"Faith is the art of holding on to things your reason once accepted, despite your changing moods."	C.S. Lewis</item>
<item>"He who loses money, loses much; He who loses a friend, loses much more, He who loses faith, loses all."	Eleanor Roosevelt</item>
<item>"Faith is not only in the heart; it should be put into words."	Nachman of Bratslav</item>
<item>"A man should believe in God through faith, not because of miracles."	Nachman of Bratslav</item>
<item>"Faithless is he that says farewell when the road darkens."	J.R.R. Tolkien</item>
<item>"If devotion to truth is the hallmark of morality, then there is no greater, nobler, more heroic form of devotion than the act of a man who assumes the responsibility of thinking...the alleged short-cut to knowledge, which is faith, is only a short-circuit destroying the mind."	Ayn Rand</item>
<item>"Your faith is what you believe, not what you know."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Until you do what you believe in, how do you know whether you believe in it or not?"	Leo Tolstoy</item>
<item>"To one who has faith, no explanation is necessary. To one without faith, no explanation is possible."	Thomas Aquinas</item>
<item>"Unless you believe, you will not understand."	Saint Augustine</item>
<item>"Most of the important things in the world have been accomplished by people who have kept on trying when there seemed to be no hope at all."	Dale Carnegie</item>
<item>"I do not pray for success, I ask for faithfulness."	Mother Teresa</item>
<item>"Reason is our soul's left hand, Faith her right."	John Donne</item>
<item>"A faith is a necessity to a man. Woe to him who believes in nothing."	Victor Hugo</item>
<item>"Love of fame is the last thing even learned men can bear to be parted from."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"Fame is a fickle food upon a shifting plate."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"In the future everyone will be world-famous for 15 minutes."	Andy Warhol</item>
<item>"Nobody has ever before asked the nuclear family to live all by itself in a box the way we do. With no relatives, no support, we've put it in an impossible situation."	Margaret Mead</item>
<item>"No government can love a child, and no policy can substitute for a family's care."	Hillary Clinton</item>
<item>"I wanted to do something nice so I bought my mother-in-law a chair. Now they won't let me plug it in."	Henny Youngman</item>
<item>"A very quiet and tasteful way to be famous is to have a famous relation. Then you can not only be nothing, you can do nothing, too."	P.J. O'Rourke</item>
<item>"If you cannot get rid of the family skeleton. You may as well make it dance."	George Bernard Shaw</item>
<item>"Men are what their mothers made them."	Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
<item>"The family you come from isn't as important as the family you're going to have."	Ring Lardner</item>
<item>"When I was a boy of 14, my father was so ignorant I could hardly stand to have the old man around. But when I got to be 21, I was astonished at how much the old man had learned in seven years."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"The one thing I want to leave my children is an honorable name."	Theodore Roosevelt</item>
<item>"Parents are not interested in justice, they're interested in peace and quiet."	Bill Cosby</item>
<item>"If the new American father feels bewildered and even defeated, let him take comfort from the fact that whatever he does in any fathering situation has a fifty percent chance of being right."	Bill Cosby</item>
<item>"Fatherhood is pretending the present you love most is soap on-a-rope."	Bill Cosby</item>
<item>"Courage is fear holding on a minute longer."	George Patton</item>
<item>"All men are timid on entering any fight. Whether it is the first or the last fight, all of us are timid. Cowards are those who let their timidity get the better of their manhood."	George Patton</item>
<item>"Fear is not in the habit of speaking truth; when perfect sincerity is expected, perfect freedom must be allowed; nor has anyone who is apt to be angry when he hears the truth any cause to wonder that he does not hear it."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"If you're afraid to ask the question, it's probably because you already know the answer."	Miriam M. Wynn</item>
<item>"There is no terror in the bang, only in the anticipation of it."	Alfred Hitchcock</item>
<item>"Neither a man nor a crowd nor a nation can be trusted to act humanely or to think sanely under the influence of a great fear."	Bertrand Russell</item>
<item>"Keep your fears to yourself, but share your inspiration with others."	Robert Louis Stevenson</item>
<item>"There is no greater hell than to be a prisoner of fear."	Ben Jonson</item>
<item>"The only thing we have to fear is fear itself - nameless, unreasoning, unjustified terror which paralyzes needed efforts to convert retreat into advance."	Franklin D. Roosevelt</item>
<item>"If you want to conquer fear, don't sit at home and think about it. Go out and get busy."	Andrew Carnegie</item>
<item>"We should not let our fears hold us back from pursuing our hopes."	John F. Kennedy</item>
<item>"I have accepted fear as a part of life - specifically the fear of change. I have gone ahead despite the pounding in the heart that says: turn back."	Erica Jong</item>
<item>"Look not back in anger, nor forward in fear, but around you in awareness."	Ross Hersey</item>
<item>"You gain strength, experience and confidence by every experience where you really stop to look fear in the face. You must do the thing you cannot do."	Eleanor Roosevelt</item>
<item>"In time we hate that which we often fear."	William Shakespeare</item>
<item>"Fear makes us feel our humanity."	Benjamin Disraeli</item>
<item>"Those who fear life are already three parts dead."	Bertrand Russell</item>
<item>"He has not learned the lesson of life who does not every day surmount a fear."	Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
<item>"There are very few monsters who warrant the fear we have of them."	André Gide</item>
<item>"The one permanent emotion of the inferior man is fear - fear of the unknown, the complex, the inexplicable. What he wants above everything else is safety."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"My fellow citizens of the world: ask not what America will do for you, but what together we can do for the freedom of man."	John F. Kennedy</item>
<item>"By our efforts, we have lit a fire as well--a fire in the minds of men. It warms those who feel its power, it burns those who fight its progress, and one day this untamed fire of freedom will reach the darkest corners of our world."	George W. Bush</item>
<item>"There is only one force of history that can break the reign of hatred and resentment, and expose the pretensions of tyrants, and reward the hopes of the decent and tolerant, and that is the force of human freedom."	George W. Bush</item>
<item>"A desire to resist oppression is implanted in the nature of man."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"Arise and take our stand for freedom as in the olden time."	Winston Churchill</item>
<item>"Americans are so enamored of equality, they would rather be equal in slavery than unequal in freedom."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"I should have loved freedom, I believe, at all times, but in the time in which we live I am ready to worship it."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"If freedom is short of weapons, we must compensate with willpower."	Adolf Hitler</item>
<item>"If a nation expects to be ignorant and free, in a state of civilization, it expects what never was and never will be."	Thomas Jefferson</item>
<item>"Freedom is not America's gift to the world, it is the Almighty God's gift to every man and woman in this world."	George W. Bush</item>
<item>"Freedom is not a gift bestowed upon us by other men, but a right that belongs to us by the laws of God and nature."	Benjamin Franklin</item>
<item>"The jaws of power are always open to devour, and her arm is always stretched out, if possible, to destroy the freedom of thinking, speaking, and writing."	John Adams</item>
<item>"If ye love wealth greater than liberty, the tranquility of servitude greater than the animating contest for freedom, go home from us in peace. We seek not your counsel, nor your arms. Crouch down and lick the hand that feeds you; May your chains set lightly upon you, and may posterity forget that ye were our countrymen."	Samuel Adams</item>
<item>"When an American says that he loves his country, he means not only that he loves the New England hills, the prairies glistening in the sun, the wide and rising plains, the great mountains, and the sea. He means that he loves an inner air, an inner light in which freedom lives and in which a man can draw the breath of self-respect."	Adlai Stevenson</item>
<item>"Just as war is freedom's cost, disagreement is freedom's privilege."	Bill Clinton</item>
<item>"Freedom is hammered out on the anvil of discussion, dissent, and debate."	Hubert H. Humphrey</item>
<item>"The trouble with fighting for human freedom is that one spends most of one's time defending scoundrels. For it is against scoundrels that oppressive laws are first aimed, and oppression must be stopped at the beginning if it is to be stopped at all."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"Freedom is the right to question and change the established way of doing things. It is the continuous revolution of the marketplace. It is the understanding that allows us to recognize shortcomings and seek solutions."	Ronald Reagan</item>
<item>"Freedom is the recognition that no single person, no single authority or government has a monopoly on the truth, but that every individual life is infinitely precious, that every one of us put in this world has been put there for a reason and has something to offer."	Ronald Reagan</item>
<item>"Our natural, inalienable rights are now considered to be a dispensation from government, and freedom has never been so fragile, so close to slipping from our grasp as it is at this moment."	Ronald Reagan</item>
<item>"Your friend is the man who knows all about you, and still likes you."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Never explain--your friends do not need it and your enemies will not believe you anyway."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Associate yourself with men of good quality if you esteem your own reputation; for 'tis better to be alone than in bad company."	George Washington</item>
<item>"Those will be thy best friends, not to whom thou hast done good, but who have done good to thee."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"My friends are my estate."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"You show people what you're willing to fight for when you fight your friends."	Hillary Clinton</item>
<item>"Friendship, like the immortality of the soul, is too good to be believed. When friendships are real, they are not glass threads or frost work, but the solidest things we know."	Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
<item>"Ultimately the bond of all companionship, wheather in marriage or in friendship, is conversation."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"No human relation gives one possession in another...every two souls are absolutely different. In friendship and in love, the two side by side raise hands together to find what one cannot reach alone."	Kahlil Gibran</item>
<item>"A friend is the hope of the heart."	Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
<item>"It is easier to forgive an enemy than to forgive a friend."	William Blake</item>
<item>"I do not want a friend who smiles when I smile, who weeps when I weep, for my shadow in the pool can do better than that."	Confucius</item>
<item>"No distance of place or lapse of time can lessen the friendship of those who are thoroughly persuaded of each other's worth."	Robert Southey</item>
<item>"Let me tell you I am better acquainted with you for a long absence, as men are with themselves for a long affliction: absence does but hold off a friend, to make one see him the truer."	Alexander Pope</item>
<item>"We call that person who has lost his father, an orphan; and a widower that man who has lost his wife. But that man who has known the immense unhappiness of losing a friend, by what name do we call him? Here every language is silent and holds its peace in impotence."	Joseph Roux</item>
<item>"Friends have all things in common."	Plato</item>
<item>"A friend is someone, who upon seeing another friend in immense pain, would rather be the one experiencing the pain than to have to watch their friend suffer."	Amanda Grier</item>
<item>"We live, in fact, in a world starved for solitude, silence, and private: and therefore starved for meditation and true friendship."	C.S. Lewis</item>
<item>"I was angry with my friend I told my wrath, my wrath did end. I was angry with my foe: I told it not, my wrath did grow."	William Blake</item>
<item>"Friendship with oneself is all-important because without it one cannot be friends with anyone else in the world."	Eleanor Roosevelt</item>
<item>"God is a verb."	Buckminster Fuller</item>
<item>"A subject for a great poet would be God's boredom after the seventh day of Creation."	Friedrich Nietzsche</item>
<item>"I sometimes think that God in creating man somewhat overestimated his ability."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"I could not say I believe — I know! I have had the experience of being gripped by something that is stronger than myself, something that people call God."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"You may think the President is all-powerful, but he is not. He needs a lot of guidance from the Lord."	Barbara Bush</item>
<item>"It is when people forget God that tyrants forge their chains."	Patrick Henry</item>
<item>"Man will ultimately be governed by God or by tyrants."	Benjamin Franklin</item>
<item>"Freedom and fear, justice and cruelty, have always been at war, and we know that God is not neutral between them."	George W. Bush</item>
<item>"I have lived, Sir, a long time, and the longer I live, the more convincing proofs I see of this truth -- that God Governs the affairs of men. And if a sparrow cannot fall to the ground without His notice, is it probable that an empire can rise without His aid?"	Benjamin Franklin</item>
<item>"This most beautiful system [The Universe] could only proceed from the dominion of an intelligent and powerful Being."	Isaac Newton</item>
<item>"They say that God is everywhere, and yet we always think of Him as somewhat of a recluse."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"God is really only another artist. He invented the giraffe, the elephant and the cat. He has no real style, He just goes on trying other things."	Pablo Picasso</item>
<item>"Cast your cares on God; that anchor holds."	Frank Moore Colby</item>
<item>"To forbid the making of pictures about God would be to forbid thinking about God at all, for man is so made that he has no way to think except in pictures."	Dorothy Sayers</item>
<item>"We do not need more intellectual power, we need more spiritual power. We do not need more of the things that are seen, we need more of the things that are unseen."	Calvin Coolidge</item>
<item>"We are commanded to love God with all our minds, as well as with all our hearts, and we commit a great sin if we forbid or prevent that cultivation of the mind in others which would enable them to perform this duty."	Angelina Grimke</item>
<item>"Question with boldness even the existence of a God; because, if there be one, he must more approve of the homage of reason, than that of blind-folded fear."	Thomas Jefferson</item>
<item>"God is a comedian playing to an audience too afraid to laugh."	Francois Marie Arouet (Voltaire)</item>
<item>"I tremble for my country when I reflect that God is just, that His justice cannot sleep forever."	Thomas Jefferson</item>
<item>"Mathematics is the language with which God has written the universe."	Galileo Galilei</item>
<item>"So long as governments set the example of killing their enemies, private individuals will occasionally kill theirs."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"A little patience, and we shall see the reign of witches pass over, their spells dissolve, and the people, recovering their true sight, restore their government to its true principles. It is true that in the meantime we are suffering deeply in spirit, and incurring the horrors of a war and long oppressions of enormous public debt...If the game runs sometime against us at home, we must have patience till luck turns, and then we shall have an opportunity of winning back the principles we have lost, for this is a game where principles are at stake."	Thomas Jefferson</item>
<item>"To those new States whom we welcome to the ranks of the free, we pledge our word that one form of colonial control shall not have passed away merely to be replaced by a far more iron tyranny."	John F. Kennedy</item>
<item>"The most dangerous moment for a bad government is when it begins to reform."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"No nation keeps its word. A nation is a big, blind worm, following what? Fate perhaps. A nation has no honor, it has no word to keep."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"I don't make jokes. I just watch the government and report the facts."	Will Rogers</item>
<item>"Be thankful we're not getting all the government we're paying for."	Will Rogers</item>
<item>"A man may be loyal to his government and yet oppose the particular principles and methods of administration."	Abraham Lincoln</item>
<item>"History, in general, only informs us what bad government is."	Thomas Jefferson</item>
<item>"The Constitution is not an instrument for the government to restrain the people, it is an instrument for the people to restrain the government -- lest it come to dominate our lives and interests."	Patrick Henry</item>
<item>"The liberties of a people never were, nor ever will be, secure, when the transactions of their rulers may be concealed from them."	Patrick Henry</item>
<item>"Now more than ever before, the people are responsible for the character of their Congress. If that body be ignorant, reckless and corrupt, it is because the people tolerate ignorance, recklessness and corruption."	James Garfield</item>
<item>"Every step we take towards making the State our Caretaker of our lives, by that much we move toward making the State our Master."	Dwight Eisenhower</item>
<item>"If ever time should come, when vain and aspiring men shall possess the highest seats in Government, our country will stand in need of its experienced patriots to prevent its ruin."	Samuel Adams</item>
<item>"In the councils of government, we must guard against the acquisition of unwarranted influence, whether sought or unsought, by the military-industrial complex."	Dwight Eisenhower</item>
<item>"The function of government ought to be: make sure you have good water to drink, somebody picking up the garbage, good roads to drive on, enough electricity to turn your light bulbs and your record player on, and whatever smaller amounts of regulatory assistance is necessary to make this society work."	Frank Zappa</item>
<item>"No government can love a child, and no policy can substitute for a family's care."	Hillary Clinton</item>
<item>"Today we can declare: Government is not the problem, and government is not the solution. We, the American people, we are the solution."	Bill Clinton</item>
<item>"The new rage is to say that the government is the cause of all our problems, and if only we had no government, we'd have no problems. I can tell you, that contradicts evidence, history, and common sense."	Bill Clinton</item>
<item>"Every government is a scoundrel."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"Get happiness out of your work or you may never know what happiness is."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Happiness serves hardly any other purpose than to make unhappiness possible."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"As soon as one is unhappy one becomes moral."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"Happiness is beneficial for the body, but it is grief that develops the powers of the mind."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"Let us be grateful to people who make us happy; they are the charming gardeners who make our souls blossom."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"Many who seem to be struggling with adversity are happy; many, amid great affluence, are utterly miserable."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"Whoever is happy will make others happy, too."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"A sound mind in a sound body is a short but full description of a happy state in this world."	John Locke</item>
<item>"Even a happy life cannot be without a measure of darkness, and the word happy would lose its meaning if it were not balanced by sadness."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"America is a vast conspiracy to make you happy."	John Updike</item>
<item>"Three grand essentials to happiness in this life are something to do, something to love, and something to hope for."	Joseph Addison</item>
<item>"Happiness is a Swedish sunset; it is there for all, but most of us look the other way and lose it."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Grief can take care of itself, but to get the full value of joy you must have somebody to divide it with."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Hope is itself a species of happiness, and, perhaps, the chief happiness which this world affords: but, like all other pleasures immoderately enjoyed, the excesses of hope must be expiated by pain; and expectations improperly indulged must end in disappointment."	Samuel Johnson</item>
<item>"Happiness is so hard to define and foolish to define. Am I acting? That's the worst thing you can ask yourself. You can be happy suddenly. It can spring on you, not when you reach a plateau. You can be happy going backward or going down. You can be happy at the loss of something."	Steve Martin</item>
<item>"My life has no purpose, no direction, no aim, no meaning, and yet I'm happy. I can't figure it out. What am I doing right?"	Charles Schulz</item>
<item>"A joyful heart is like the sunshine of God's love, the hope of eternal happiness."	Mother Teresa</item>
<item>"The art of being happy lies in the power of extracting happiness from common things."	Henry Ward Beecher</item>
<item>"Man needs, for his happiness, not only the enjoyment of this or that, but hope and enterprise and change."	Bertrand Russell</item>
<item>"What is happiness? The feeling that power is growing, that resistance is overcome."	Friedrich Nietzsche</item>
<item>"History is more or less bunk."	Henry Ford</item>
<item>"History is a gallery of pictures in which there are few originals and many copies."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"The man who has no sense of history, is like a man who has no ears or eyes."	Adolf Hitler</item>
<item>"There is nothing new in the world except the history you do not know."	Harry Truman</item>
<item>"History doesn't repeat itself, but it does rhyme."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Well, the telling of jokes is an art of its own, and it always rises from some emotional threat. The best jokes are dangerous, and dangerous because they are in some way truthful."	Kurt Vonnegut</item>
<item>"Kids like my act because I'm wearing nose glasses. Adults like my act because there's a guy who thinks putting on nose glasses is funny."	Steve Martin</item>
<item>"In the end, everything is a gag."	Charlie Chaplin</item>
<item>"Anyone without a sense of humor is at the mercy of everyone else."	William Rotsler</item>
<item>"Humor is the only test of gravity, and gravity of humor; for a subject which will not bear raillery is suspicious, and a jest which will not bear serious examination is false wit."	Aristotle</item>
<item>"Life does not cease to be funny when people die any more than it ceases to be serious when people laugh."	George Bernard Shaw</item>
<item>"Comedy is the art of making people laugh without making them puke."	Steve Martin</item>
<item>"Chaos in the midst of chaos isn't funny, but chaos in the midst of order is."	Steve Martin</item>
<item>"I think it's the duty of the comedian to find out where the line is drawn and cross it deliberately."	George Carlin</item>
<item>"You can turn painful situations around through laughter. If you can find humor in anything, even poverty, you can survive it."	Bill Cosby</item>
<item>"Humor is the great thing, the saving thing. The minute it crops up, all our irritation and resentments slip away, and a sunny spirit takes their place."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"Humor is mankind's greatest blessing."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"The secret to humor is surprise."	Aristotle</item>
<item>"Humor is the most engaging cowardice."	Robert Frost</item>
<item>"Analyzing humor is like dissecting a frog. Few people are interested and the frog dies of it."	E.B. White</item>
<item>"Humor is perhaps a sense of intellectual perspective: an awareness that some things are really important, others not; and that the two kinds are most oddly jumbled in everyday affairs."	Christopher Morley</item>
<item>"To be what we are, and to become what we are capable of becoming, is the only end of life."	Robert Louis Stevenson</item>
<item>"Life is just one damned thing after another."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Alas, I am dying beyond my means."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"Life consists not in holding good cards but in playing those you hold well."	Josh Billings</item>
<item>"Absence and death are the same - only that in death there is no suffering."	Theodore Roosevelt</item>
<item>"Life is to entered upon with courage."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"Death is psychologically as important as birth. Shrinking away from it is something unhealthy and abnormal which robs the second half of life of its purpose."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"A shoe that fits one person pinches another; there is no recipe for living that suits all cases."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"As far as we can discern, the sole purpose of human existence is to kindle a light of meaning in the darkness of mere being."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"It is not death that a man should fear, but he should fear never beginning to live."	Marcus Aurelius</item>
<item>"For three days after death, hair and fingernails continue to grow but phone calls taper off."	Johnny Carson</item>
<item>"To live is so startling it leaves little time for anything else."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"Dying is the most embarrassing thing that can ever happen to you, because someone's got to take care of all your details."	Andy Warhol</item>
<item>"Life is ours to be spent, not to be saved."	D.H. Lawrence</item>
<item>"In the life of a man, his time is but a moment...his sense, a dim rushlight. All that is body is as coursing waters...all that is of the soul, as dreams, and vapors."	Marcus Aurelius</item>
<item>"A single death is a tragedy; a million deaths is a statistic."	Joseph Stalin</item>
<item>"Dying is a very dull, dreary affair. And my advice to you is to have nothing whatever to do with it."	W. Somerset Maugham</item>
<item>"He not busy being born is busy dying."	Bob Dylan</item>
<item>"As a well-spent day brings happy sleep, so life well used brings happy death."	Leonardo da Vinci</item>
<item>"Life is pleasant. Death is peaceful. It's the transition that's troublesome."	Isaac Asimov</item>
<item>"The essence of romantic love is not the company of a lover but the pursuit."	Andrew Sullivan</item>
<item>"The love we give away is the only love we keep."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Life in abundance comes only through great love."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Those who are faithful know only the trivial side of love: it is the faithless who know love's tragedies."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"In a separation it is the one who is not really in love who says the more tender things."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"What a profound significance small things assume when the woman we love conceals them from us."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"In his younger days a man dreams of possessing the heart of the woman whom he loves; later, the feeling that he possesses the heart of a woman may be enough to make him fall in love with her."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"People who are not in love fail to understand how an intelligent man can suffer because of a very ordinary woman. This is like being surprised that anyone should be stricken with cholera because of a creature so insignificant as the comma bacillus."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"Where love rules, there is no will to power; and where power predominates, there love is lacking. The one is the shadow of the other."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"Love yourself first and everything else falls into line. You really have to love yourself to get anything done in this world."	Lucille Ball</item>
<item>"If thou rememb'rest not the slightest folly into which love hast made thee run, though hast not loved."	William Shakespeare</item>
<item>"Where there is no exaggeration there is no love, and where there is no love there is no understanding."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"Love is repaid by love alone!"	Mother Teresa</item>
<item>"Love is like war: easy to begin but very hard to stop."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"My wife is as handsome as when she was a girl, and I...fell in love with her; and what is more, I have never fallen out."	Abraham Lincoln</item>
<item>"Love sought is good, but given unsought is better."	William Shakespeare</item>
<item>"And what’s romance? Usually, a nice little tale where you have everything As You Like It, where rain never wets your jacket and gnats never bite your nose and it’s always daisy-time."	D.H. Lawrence</item>
<item>"Mortal lovers must not try to remain at the first step; for lasting passion is the dream of a harlot and from it we wake in despair."	C.S. Lewis</item>
<item>"Pure love and suspicion cannot dwell together: at the door where the latter enters, the former makes its exit."	Alexandre Dumas</item>
<item>"The fickleness of the women I love is only equaled by the infernal constancy of the women who love me."	George Bernard Shaw</item>
<item>"What is the most important for democracy is not that great fortunes should not exist, but that great fortunes should not remain in the same hands. In that way there are rich men, but they do not form a class."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"Nothing is quite so wretchedly corrupt as an aristocracy which has lost its power but kept its wealth and which still has endless leisure to devote to nothing but banal enjoyments. All its great thoughts and passionate energy are things of the past, and nothing but a host of petty, gnawing vices now cling to it like worms to a corpse."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"The only thing money gives you is the freedom of not worrying about money."	Johnny Carson</item>
<item>"The greatest wealth is to live content with little."	Plato</item>
<item>"I paid too much for it, but it's worth it."	Samuel Goldwyn</item>
<item>"The chief value of money lies in the fact that one lives in a world in which it is overestimated."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"Never confuse the size of your paycheck with the size of your talent."	Marlon Brando</item>
<item>"Many wealthy people are little more than janitors of their possessions."	Frank Lloyd Wright</item>
<item>"It is preoccupation with possessions, more than anything else, that prevents us from living freely and nobly."	Bertrand Russell</item>
<item>"Money is better than poverty, if only for financial reasons."	Woody Allen</item>
<item>"A man has one hundred dollars and you leave him with two dollars, that's subtraction."	Mae West</item>
<item>"Enjoy your job, make lots of money, work within the law. Choose any two."	Author Unknown</item>
<item>"So you think that money is the root of all evil. Have you ever asked what is the root of all money?"	Ayn Rand</item>
<item>"It made me sick to watch those businessmen applaud Welles during the 1975 AFI tribute, when you know that the next day if he asked any one of them for money, they'd say, 'We'll let you know.'""	John Cassavettes</item>
<item>"I think that much of the advice given to young men about saving money is wrong. I never saved a cent until I was forty years old. I invested in myself - in study, in mastering my tools, in preparation. Many a man who is putting a few dollars a week into the bank would do much better to put it into himself."	Henry Ford</item>
<item>"Wealth is the parent of luxury and indolence, and poverty of meanness and viciousness, and both of discontent."	Plato</item>
<item>"The two most beautiful words in the English language are 'check enclosed.'"	Dorothy Parker</item>
<item>"I am indeed rich, since my income is superior to my expense, and my expense is equal to my wishes."	Kahlil Gibran</item>
<item>"Money is like a sixth sense without which you cannot make a complete use of the other five."	W. Somerset Maugham</item>
<item>"I never hated a man enough to give him diamonds back."	Zsa Zsa Gabor</item>
<item>"The nationalist not only does not disapprove of atrocities committed by his own side, but he has a remarkable capacity for not even hearing about them."	George Orwell</item>
<item>"Patriotism is the last refuge of a scoundrel."	Samuel Johnson</item>
<item>"Patriotism is easy to understand in America. It means looking out for yourself by looking out for your country."	Calvin Coolidge</item>
<item>"Some of your countrymen were unable to distinguish between their native dislike for war and the stainless patriotism of those who suffered its scars. But there has been a rethinking and now we can say to you, and say as a nation, thank you for your courage."	Ronald Reagan</item>
<item>"One of the great attractions of patriotism -- it fulfills our worst wishes. In the person of our nation we are able, vicariously, to bully and cheat. Bully and cheat, what's more, with a feeling that we are profoundly virtuous."	Aldous Huxley</item>
<item>"Heroism at command, senseless brutality, and all the loathsome nonsense that goes by the name of patriotism, how violently I hate all this, how despicable and ignoble war is; I would rather be torn to shreds than be part of so base an action!"	Albert Einstein</item>
<item>"True patriotism hates injustice in its own land more than anywhere else."	Clarence Darrow</item>
<item>"Patriotism is the virtue of the vicious."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"But could not our situation be compared to one of a menacing epidemic? People are unable to view this situation in its true light, for their eyes are blinded by passion. General fear and anxiety create hatred and aggressiveness. The adaptation to warlike aims and activities has corrupted the mentality of man; as a result, intelligent, objective and humane thinking has hardly any effect and is even suspected and persecuted as unpatriotic."	Albert Einstein</item>
<item>"When a whole nation is roaring patriotism at the top of its voice, I am fain to explore the cleanness of its hands and purity of its heart."	Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
<item>"My country, right or wrong' is a thing no patriot would ever think of saying except in a desperate case. It is like saying 'My mother, drunk or sober.'"	GK Chesterton</item>
<item>"Our true nationality is mankind."	H.G. Wells</item>
<item>"Ask not what your country can do for you - ask what you can do for your country."	John F. Kennedy</item>
<item>"Patriotism is your conviction that this country is superior to all other countries because you were born in it."	George Bernard Shaw</item>
<item>"Patriotism is not short, frenzied outbursts of emotion, but the tranquil and steady dedication of a lifetime."	Adlai Stevenson</item>
<item>"I have nothing to offer but blood, toil, tears and sweat."	Winston Churchill</item>
<item>"Power is not a means, it is an end. One does not establish a dictatorship in order to safeguard a revolution; one makes the revolution in order to establish the dictatorship."	George Orwell</item>
<item>"Where love rules, there is no will to power; and where power predominates, there love is lacking. The one is the shadow of the other."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"What is happiness? The feeling that power is growing, that resistance is overcome."	Friedrich Nietzsche</item>
<item>"What is good? Everything that heightens the feeling of power in man, the will to power, power itself."	Friedrich Nietzsche</item>
<item>"Through pride we are ever deceiving ourselves. But deep down below the surface of the average conscience a still, small voice says to us, something is out of tune."	Carl Jung</item>
<item>"He that falls in love with himself will have no rivals."	Benjamin Franklin</item>
<item>"A proud man is always looking down on things and people; and, of course, as long as you're looking down, you can't see something that's above you."	C.S. Lewis</item>
<item>"The man who acts humble in order to win praise is guilty of the lowest form of pride."	Nachman of Bratslav</item>
<item>"But we have forgotten God. We have forgotten the gracious Hand which preserved us in peace, and multiplied and enriched and strengthened us; and we have vainly imagined, in the deceitfulness of our hearts, that all these blessings were produced by some superior wisdom and virtue of our own."	Abraham Lincoln</item>
<item>"The essence of a self-reliant and autonomous culture is an unshakeable egoism."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"There is a paradox in pride: it makes some men ridiculous, but prevents others from becoming so."	Charles Caleb Colton</item>
<item>"Pride gets no pleasure out of having something, only out of having more of it than the next man."	C.S. Lewis</item>
<item>"Swallow your pride occasionally, it's not fattening."	Frank Tyger</item>
<item>"Pride is an admission of weakness; it secretly fears all competition and dreads all rivals."	Fulton J. Sheen</item>
<item>"It would be fatal for the nation to overlook the urgency of the moment. This sweltering summer of the Negro's legitimate discontent will not pass until there is an invigorating autumn of freedom and equality."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"I don't believe in quotas. America was founded on a philosophy of individual rights, not group rights."	Clarence Thomas</item>
<item>"There can be no doubt that racial paternalism and its unintended consequences can be as poisonous and pernicious as any other form of discrimination."	Clarence Thomas</item>
<item>"People sometimes ask if I have tried to convince black 'leaders' to take a different view on racial issues. Of course not. I wouldn't spend my time trying to persuade the mafia to give up crime. Why should I spend time trying to convince race hustlers to give up victimhood? It's their bread and butter."	Thomas Sowell</item>
<item>"I detest racialism, because I regard it as a barbaric thing, whether it comes from a black man or a white man."	Nelson Mandela</item>
<item>"I think it's insulting to people who have a heritage of slavery to compare the homosexual experience in America to that. It's an unfortunate, cheap attempt to piggyback on something and to co-opt life experiences of others, claim that you've experienced them yourselves so that you can advance a cause."	Rush Limbaugh</item>
<item>"It is incontestable and deplorable that Negroes have committed crimes; but they are derivative crimes. They are born of the greater crimes of the white society."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"Many interviewers when they come to talk to me, think they're being progressive by not mentioning in their stories any longer that I'm black. I tell them, 'Don't stop now. If I shot somebody you'd mention it.'"	Colin Powell</item>
<item>"When we're unemployed, we're called lazy; when the whites are unemployed it's called a depression."	Jesse Jackson</item>
<item>"I want to be the white man's brother, not his brother-in-law."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"Before the Pilgrims landed at Plymouth, we were here. Before the pen of Jefferson etched across the pages of history the majestic words of the Declaration of Independence, we were here. If the inexpressible cruelties of slavery could not stop us, the opposition we now face will surely fail."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"The Negro needs the white man to free him from his fears. The white man needs the Negro to free him from his guilt."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"Our nettlesome task is to discover how to organize our strength into compelling power."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin, but by the content of their character."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"Violence as a way of achieving racial justice is both impractical and immoral. It is impractical because it is a descending spiral ending in destruction for all. It is immoral because it seeks to humiliate the opponent rather than win his understanding; it seeks to annihilate rather than to convert. Violence is immoral because it thrives on hatred rather than love."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"Some succeed by what they know; some by what they do; and a few by what they are."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"The line between failure and success is so fine that we scarcely know when we pass it; so fine that we are often on the line and do not know it."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"It is only by doing things others have not that one can advance."	George Patton</item>
<item>"The harder the conflict, the more glorious the triumph. What we obtain too cheap, we esteem too lightly. 'Tis dearness only that gives everything its value."	Thomas Paine</item>
<item>"We must never be afraid to go too far, for success lies just beyond."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"We succeed in enterprises which demand the positive qualities we possess, but we excel in those which can also make use of our defects."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"Success is a lousy teacher. It seduces smart people into thinking they can't lose."	Bill Gates</item>
<item>"Don't measure yourself by what you have accomplished, but by what you should have accomplished with your ability."	John Wooden</item>
<item>"Talent alone won't make you a success. Neither will being in the right place at the right time, unless you are ready. The most important question is: 'Are you ready?'"	Johnny Carson</item>
<item>"My success just evolved from working hard at the business at hand each day."	Johnny Carson</item>
<item>"Success is counted sweetest by those who ne'er succeed."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"No man, who continues to add something to the material, intellectual and moral well-being of the place in which he lives, is left long without proper reward."	Booker T. Washington</item>
<item>"Pick battles big enough to matter, small enough to win."	Jonathan Kozol</item>
<item>"Life's battles don't always go to the stronger or faster man. But sooner or later the man who wins, is the man who thinks he can."	Vince Lombardi</item>
<item>"Don't confuse having a career with having a life."	Hillary Clinton</item>
<item>"Men are born to succeed, not fail."	Henry Thoreau</item>
<item>"Be not afraid of greatness. Some are born great, some achieve greatness, and some have greatness thrust upon 'em."	William Shakespeare</item>
<item>"I have found some of the best reasons I ever had for remaining at the bottom simply by looking at the men at the top."	Frank Moore Colby</item>
<item>"Let us be thankful for the fools. But for them the rest of us could not succeed."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"No enterprise can exist for itself alone. It ministers to some great need, it performs some great service, not for itself, but for others; or failing therein, it ceases to be profitable and ceases to exist."	Calvin Coolidge</item>
<item>"Strength of mind is exercise, not rest."	Alexander Pope</item>
<item>"If you are going to win any battle, you have to do one thing. You have to make the mind run the body. Never let the body tell the mind what to do... the body is never tired if the mind is not tired."	George Patton</item>
<item>"If everyone is thinking alike, someone isn't thinking."	George Patton</item>
<item>"Any mental activity is easy if it need not take reality into account."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"Happiness is beneficial for the body, but it is grief that develops the powers of the mind."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"In the United States the majority undertakes to supply a multitude of ready-made opinions for the use of individuals, who are thus relieved from the necessity of forming opinions of their own."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"I have always thought the actions of men the best interpreters of their thoughts."	John Locke</item>
<item>"I think; therefore I am."	Rene Descartes</item>
<item>"This is slavery, not to speak one's thought."	Euripides</item>
<item>"That is the consolation of a little mind; you have the fun of changing it without impeding the progress of mankind."	Frank Moore Colby</item>
<item>"Few people think more than two or three times a year. I have made an international reputation for myself by thinking once or twice a week."	George Bernard Shaw</item>
<item>"It is your mind that creates this world."	Siddhartha Buddha</item>
<item>"Great spirits have always encountered violent oppostion from mediocre minds."	Albert Einstein</item>
<item>"Learning without thought is labor lost."	Confucius</item>
<item>"Nothing pains some people more than having to think."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"Rarely do we find men who willingly engage in hard, solid thinking. There is an almost universal quest for easy answers and half-baked solutions."	Martin Luther King Jr.</item>
<item>"To think is to differ."	Clarence Darrow</item>
<item>"In the small matters trust the mind, in the large ones the heart."	Sigmund Freud</item>
<item>"Reason is experimental intelligence, conceived after the pattern of science, and used in the creation of social arts; it has something to do. It liberates man from the bondage of the past, due to ignorance and accident hardened into custom. It projects a better future and assists man in its realization."	John Dewey</item>
<item>"I'll be more enthusiastic about encouraging thinking outside the box when there's evidence of any thinking going on inside it."	Terry Pratchett</item>
<item>"Everything comes too late for those who only wait."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"It is only the modern that ever becomes old-fashioned."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"We have it in our power to begin the world over again."	Thomas Paine</item>
<item>"The moments of the past do not remain still; they retain in our memory the motion which drew them towards the future, towards a future which has itself become the past, and draw us on in their train."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"Time passes, and little by little everything that we have spoken in falsehood becomes true."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"The time which we have at our disposal every day is elastic; the passions we feel expand it, those that we inspire contract it, and habit fills up what remains."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"Time, which changes people, does not alter the image we have retained of them."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"He who controls the present, controls the past. He who controls the past, controls the future."	George Orwell</item>
<item>"When the past no longer illuminates the future, the spirit walks in darkness."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"Like as the waves make towards the pebbl'd shore, so do our minutes hasten to their end."	William Shakespeare</item>
<item>"We always overestimate the change that will occur in the next two years and underestimate the change that will occur in the next ten."	Bill Gates</item>
<item>"I confess, I do not believe in time."	Vladimir Nabokov</item>
<item>"But what minutes! Count them by sensation, and not by calendars, and each moment is a day."	Benjamin Disraeli</item>
<item>"Time has been transformed, and we have changed; it has advanced and set us in motion; it has unveiled its face, inspiring us with bewilderment and exhilaration."	Kahlil Gibran</item>
<item>"Forever is composed of nows."	Emily Dickinson</item>
<item>"They always say time changes things, but you actually have to change them yourself."	Andy Warhol</item>
<item>"Eternity's a terrible thought. I mean, where's it all going to end?"	Tom Stoppard</item>
<item>"I've seen the future, and it's much like the present -- only longer."	Dan Quisenberry</item>
<item>"The best thing about the future is that it comes only one day at a time."	Abraham Lincoln</item>
<item>"As if you could kill time without injuring eternity."	Henry Thoreau</item>
<item>"Either war is obsolete or men are."	Buckminster Fuller</item>
<item>"It is the unconquerable nature of man and not the nature of the weapon he uses that ensures victory."	George Patton</item>
<item>"I am a soldier, I fight where I am told, and I win where I fight."	George Patton</item>
<item>"May God have mercy upon my enemies, because I won't."	George Patton</item>
<item>"All men are timid on entering any fight. Whether it is the first or the last fight, all of us are timid. Cowards are those who let their timidity get the better of their manhood."	George Patton</item>
<item>"War is an art and as such is not susceptible of explanation by fixed formula."	George Patton</item>
<item>"There is nothing easier than lopping off heads and nothing harder than developing ideas."	Fyodor Dostoevsky</item>
<item>"The battle is now joined on many fronts. We will not waver; we will not tire; we will not falter; and we will not fail."	George W. Bush</item>
<item>"It is only necessary to make war with five things: with the maladies of the body, with the ignorances of the mind, with the passions of the body, with the seditions of the city, with the discords of families."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"He that fights and runs away, may turn and fight another day; but he that is in battle slain, will never rise to fight again."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"A bad peace is even worse than war."	Tacitus</item>
<item>"People sleep peaceably in their beds at night only because rough men stand ready to do violence on their behalf."	George Orwell</item>
<item>"There are two things which a democratic people will always find very difficult - to begin a war and to end it."	Alexis de Tocqueville</item>
<item>"Short-circuiting the long-established principles of patient negotiation leads to war, not peace."	Jimmy Carter</item>
<item>"Wars may be fought with weapons, but they are won by men."	George Patton</item>
<item>"I would rather have peace in the world than be President."	Harry Truman</item>
<item>"Demoralize the enemy from within by surprise, terror, sabotage, assassination. This is the war of the future."	Adolf Hitler</item>
<item>"Strength lies not in defense but in attack."	Adolf Hitler</item>
<item>"Those who want to live, let them fight, and those who do not want to fight in this world of eternal struggle do not deserve to live."	Adolf Hitler</item>
<item>"The battle, Sir, is not to the strong alone; it is to the vigilant, the active, the brave."	Patrick Henry</item>
<item>"No man is so foolish but he may sometimes give another good counsel, and no man so wise that he may not easily err if he takes no other counsel than his own. He that is taught only by himself has a fool for a master."	Hunter S. Thompson</item>
<item>"A word to the wise is infuriating."	Hunter S. Thompson</item>
<item>"The well-bred contradict other people. The wise contradict themselves."	Oscar Wilde</item>
<item>"The wise man learns more from the fool than the fool learns from the wise man."	Marcus Aurelius</item>
<item>"We don't receive wisdom; we must discover it for ourselves after a journey that no one can take for us or spare us."	Marcel Proust</item>
<item>"The older I grow the more I distrust the familiar doctrine that age brings wisdom."	Henry Mencken</item>
<item>"Knowledge comes, but wisdom lingers."	Calvin Coolidge</item>
<item>"It requires wisdom to understand wisdom: the music is nothing if the audience is deaf."	Walter Lippman</item>
<item>"The highest form of wisdom is to get drunk and go to pieces."	Rudyard Kipling</item>
<item>"What wisdom can you find that is greater than kindness?"	Jean-Jacques Rousseau</item>
<item>"Knowledge is not wisdom, unless used wisely."	J.D. Anderson</item>
<item>"How I wish that somewhere there existed an island for those who are wise and of goodwill! In such a place even I would be an ardent patriot."	Albert Einstein</item>
<item>"The fool doth think he is wise, but the wise man knows himself to be a fool."	William Shakespeare</item>
<item>"The wise speak only of what they know."	J.R.R. Tolkien</item>
<item>"In doubt a man of worth will trust to his own wisdom."	J.R.R. Tolkien</item>
<item>"Wisdom begins at the end."	Daniel Webster</item>
<item>"Age does not always bring wisdom. Sometimes age comes alone."	Garrison Keillor</item>
<item>"Without courage, wisdom bears no fruit."	Baltasar Gracian</item>
<item>"A wise man gets more use from his enemies than a fool from his friends."	Baltasar Gracian</item>
<item>"The wise man does at once what the fool does finally."	Baltasar Gracian</item>
<item>"I have a theory that the truth is never told during the nine-to-five hours."	Hunter S. Thompson</item>
<item>"Get happiness out of your work or you may never know what happiness is."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Never continue in a job you don't enjoy. If you're happy in what you're doing, you'll like yourself, you'll have inner peace. And if you have that, along with physical health, you will have had more success than you could possibly have imagined."	Johnny Carson</item>
<item>"The more man puts into God, the less he retains in himself. The worker puts his life into the object; but now his life no longer belongs to him, but to the object."	Karl Marx</item>
<item>"The mode by which the inevitable comes to pass is effort."	Oliver Wendell Holmes</item>
<item>"If I am anything, which I highly doubt, I have made myself so by hard work."	Isaac Newton</item>
<item>"Inspiration exists, but it has to find you working."	Pablo Picasso</item>
<item>"All growth depends upon activity. There is no development physically or intellectually without effort, and effort means work."	Calvin Coolidge</item>
<item>"Enjoy your job, make lots of money, work within the law. Choose any two."	Author Unknown</item>
<item>"I do not like work even when someone else does it."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"If you don't know what to do with many of the papers piled on your desk, stick a dozen colleagues' initials on 'em, and pass them along. When in doubt, route."	Malcolm Forbes</item>
<item>"The beginning is the most important part of the work."	Plato</item>
<item>"If women are expected to do the same work as men, we must teach them the same things."	Plato</item>
<item>"When you work seven days a week, fourteen hours a day, you get lucky."	Armand Hammer</item>
<item>"The days you work are the best days."	Georgia O'Keefe</item>
<item>"When nothing seems to help, I go and look at a stonecutter hammering away at his rock perhaps a hundred times without as much as a crack showing in it. Yet at the hundred and first blow it will split in two, and I know it was not that blow that did it, but all that had gone before."	Jacob August Riis</item>
<item>"Thinking is the hardest work there is, which is the probable reason why so few engage in it."	Henry Ford</item>
<item>"The world is moving so fast these days that the man who says it can't be done is generally interrupted by someone doing it."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"If God is satisfied with the work, the work may be satisfied with itself."	C.S. Lewis</item>
<item>"I am a strong believer in luck and I find the harder I work the more I have of it."	Benjamin Franklin</item>
<item>"I have a theory that the truth is never told during the nine-to-five hours."	Hunter S. Thompson</item>
<item>"Get happiness out of your work or you may never know what happiness is."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"Never continue in a job you don't enjoy. If you're happy in what you're doing, you'll like yourself, you'll have inner peace. And if you have that, along with physical health, you will have had more success than you could possibly have imagined."	Johnny Carson</item>
<item>"The more man puts into God, the less he retains in himself. The worker puts his life into the object; but now his life no longer belongs to him, but to the object."	Karl Marx</item>
<item>"The mode by which the inevitable comes to pass is effort."	Oliver Wendell Holmes</item>
<item>"If I am anything, which I highly doubt, I have made myself so by hard work."	Isaac Newton</item>
<item>"Inspiration exists, but it has to find you working."	Pablo Picasso</item>
<item>"All growth depends upon activity. There is no development physically or intellectually without effort, and effort means work."	Calvin Coolidge</item>
<item>"Enjoy your job, make lots of money, work within the law. Choose any two."	Author Unknown</item>
<item>"I do not like work even when someone else does it."	Mark Twain</item>
<item>"If you don't know what to do with many of the papers piled on your desk, stick a dozen colleagues' initials on 'em, and pass them along. When in doubt, route."	Malcolm Forbes</item>
<item>"The beginning is the most important part of the work."	Plato</item>
<item>"If women are expected to do the same work as men, we must teach them the same things."	Plato</item>
<item>"When you work seven days a week, fourteen hours a day, you get lucky."	Armand Hammer</item>
<item>"The days you work are the best days."	Georgia O'Keefe</item>
<item>"When nothing seems to help, I go and look at a stonecutter hammering away at his rock perhaps a hundred times without as much as a crack showing in it. Yet at the hundred and first blow it will split in two, and I know it was not that blow that did it, but all that had gone before."	Jacob August Riis</item>
<item>"Thinking is the hardest work there is, which is the probable reason why so few engage in it."	Henry Ford</item>
<item>"The world is moving so fast these days that the man who says it can't be done is generally interrupted by someone doing it."	Elbert Hubbard</item>
<item>"If God is satisfied with the work, the work may be satisfied with itself."	C.S. Lewis</item>
<item>"I am a strong believer in luck and I find the harder I work the more I have of it."	Benjamin Franklin</item>
</array>

<array name="bible">
<item>And the LORD God said, It is not good that the man should be alone; I will make him an help meet for him. (Genesis 2:18)</item>
<item>And Adam said, This is now bone of my bones, and flesh of my flesh: she shall be called Woman, because she was taken out of Man. Therefore shall a man leave his father and his mother, and shall cleave unto his wife: and they shall be one flesh. (Genesis 2:23-24)</item>
<item>In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread, till thou return unto the ground; for out of it wast thou taken: for dust thou art, and unto dust shalt thou return. (Genesis 3:19)</item>
<item>Whoso sheddeth man's blood, by man shall his blood be shed: for in the image of God made he man. (Genesis 9:6)</item>
<item>Thou shalt not avenge, nor bear any grudge against the children of thy people, but thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself: I am the LORD. (Leviticus 19:18)</item>
<item>The LORD bless thee, and keep thee: The LORD make his face shine upon thee, and be gracious unto thee: The LORD lift up his countenance upon thee, and give thee peace. (Numbers 6:24-26)</item>
<item>(For the LORD thy God is a merciful God;) he will not forsake thee, neither destroy thee, nor forget the covenant of thy fathers which he sware unto them. (Deuteronomy 4:31)</item>
<item>But thou shalt remember the LORD thy God: for it is he that giveth thee power to get wealth, that he may establish his covenant which he sware unto thy fathers, as it is this day. (Deuteronomy 8:18)</item>
<item>And now, Israel, what doth the LORD thy God require of thee, but to fear the LORD thy God, to walk in all his ways, and to love him, and to serve the LORD thy God with all thy heart and with all thy soul, (Deuteronomy 10:12)</item>
<item>The secret things belong unto the LORD our God: but those things which are revealed belong unto us and to our children for ever, that we may do all the words of this law. (Deuteronomy 29:29)</item>
<item>Be strong and of a good courage, fear not, nor be afraid of them: for the LORD thy God, he it is that doth go with thee; he will not fail thee, nor forsake thee. (Deuteronomy 31:6)</item>
<item>Have not I commanded thee? Be strong and of a good courage; be not afraid, neither be thou dismayed: for the LORD thy God is with thee whithersoever thou goest. (Joshua 1:9)</item>
<item>But the LORD said unto Samuel, Look not on his countenance, or on the height of his stature; because I have refused him: for the LORD seeth not as man seeth; for man looketh on the outward appearance, but the LORD looketh on the heart. (1 Samuel 16:7)</item>
<item>And keep the charge of the LORD thy God, to walk in his ways, to keep his statutes, and his commandments, and his judgments, and his testimonies, as it is written in the law of Moses, that thou mayest prosper in all that thou doest, and whithersoever thou turnest thyself: (1 Kings 2:3)</item>
<item>And the king of Israel answered and said, Tell him, Let not him that girdeth on his harness boast himself as he that putteth it off. (1 Kings 20:11)</item>
<item>But the LORD your God ye shall fear; and he shall deliver you out of the hand of all your enemies. (2 Kings 17:39)</item>
<item>Both riches and honour come of thee, and thou reignest over all; and in thine hand is power and might; and in thine hand it is to make great, and to give strength unto all. (1 Chronicles 29:12)</item>
<item>If my people, which are called by my name, shall humble themselves, and pray, and seek my face, and turn from their wicked ways; then will I hear from heaven, and will forgive their sin, and will heal their land. (2 Chronicles 7:14)</item>
<item>Be ye strong therefore, and let not your hands be weak: for your work shall be rewarded. (2 Chronicles 15:7)</item>
<item>For if ye turn again unto the LORD, your brethren and your children shall find compassion before them that lead them captive, so that they shall come again into this land: for the LORD your God is gracious and merciful, and will not turn away his face from you, if ye return unto him. (2 Chronicles 30:9)</item>
<item>...Naked came I out of my mother's womb, and naked shall I return thither: the LORD gave, and the LORD hath taken away; blessed be the name of the LORD. (Job 1:21)</item>
<item>Even as I have seen, they that plow iniquity, and sow wickedness, reap the same. (Job 4:8)</item>
<item>They that hate thee shall be clothed with shame; and the dwelling place of the wicked shall come to nought. (Job 8:22)</item>
<item>But ask now the beasts, and they shall teach thee; and the fowls of the air, and they shall tell thee: Or speak to the earth, and it shall teach thee: and the fishes of the sea shall declare unto thee. (Job 12:7-8)</item>
<item>How oft is the candle of the wicked put out! and how oft cometh their destruction upon them! God distributeth sorrows in his anger. (Job 21:17)</item>
<item>No mention shall be made of coral, or of pearls: for the price of wisdom is above rubies. (Job 28:18)</item>
<item>I was eyes to the blind, and feet was I to the lame. (Job 29:15)</item>
<item>I said, Days should speak, and multitude of years should teach wisdom. (Job 32:7)</item>
<item>Great men are not always wise: neither do the aged understand judgment. (Job 32:9)</item>
<item>If they obey and serve him, they shall spend their days in prosperity, and their years in pleasures. (Job 36:11)</item>
<item>With the merciful thou wilt shew thyself merciful; with an upright man thou wilt shew thyself upright; (Psalms 18:25)</item>
<item>The heavens declare the glory of God; and the firmament sheweth his handywork. (Psalms 19:1)</item>
<item>The LORD is my shepherd; I shall not want. (Psalms 23:1)</item>
<item>He maketh me to lie down in green pastures: he leadeth me beside the still waters. (Psalms 23:2)</item>
<item>Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil: for thou art with me; thy rod and thy staff they comfort me. (Psalms 23:4)</item>
<item>Sing unto the LORD, O ye saints of his, and give thanks at the remembrance of his holiness. (Psalms 30:4)</item>
<item>Thou art my hiding place; thou shalt preserve me from trouble; thou shalt compass me about with songs of deliverance. Selah. (Psalms 32:7)</item>
<item>Many sorrows shall be to the wicked: but he that trusteth in the LORD, mercy shall compass him about. (Psalms 32:10)</item>
<item>The young lions do lack, and suffer hunger: but they that seek the LORD shall not want any good thing. (Psalms 34:10)</item>
<item>Keep thy tongue from evil, and thy lips from speaking guile. (Psalms 34:13)</item>
<item>Depart from evil, and do good; seek peace, and pursue it. (Psalms 34:14)</item>
<item>Fret not thyself because of evildoers, neither be thou envious against the workers of iniquity. (Psalms 37:1)</item>
<item>Rest in the LORD, and wait patiently for him: fret not thyself because of him who prospereth in his way, because of the man who bringeth wicked devices to pass. (Psalms 37:7)</item>
<item>A little that a righteous man hath is better than the riches of many wicked. (Psalms 37:16)</item>
<item>Mark the perfect man, and behold the upright: for the end of that man is peace. (Psalms 37:37)</item>
<item>LORD, make me to know mine end, and the measure of my days, what it is: that I may know how frail I am. (Psalms 39:4)</item>
<item>Blessed is he that considereth the poor: the LORD will deliver him in time of trouble. (Psalms 41:1)</item>
<item>God is our refuge and strength, a very present help in trouble. (Psalms 46:1)</item>
<item>Create in me a clean heart, O God; and renew a right spirit within me. (Psalms 51:10)</item>
<item>Cast thy burden upon the LORD, and he shall sustain thee: he shall never suffer the righteous to be moved. (Psalms 55:22)</item>
<item>In God have I put my trust: I will not be afraid what man can do unto me. (Psalms 56:11)</item>
<item>Truly my soul waiteth upon God: from him cometh my salvation. (Psalms 62:1)</item>
<item>In God is my salvation and my glory: the rock of my strength, and my refuge, is in God. (Psalms 62:7)</item>
<item>My flesh and my heart faileth: but God is the strength of my heart, and my portion for ever. (Psalms 73:26)</item>
<item>For the LORD God is a sun and shield: the LORD will give grace and glory: no good thing will he withhold from them that walk uprightly. (Psalms 84:11)</item>
<item>The righteous shall flourish like the palm tree: he shall grow like a cedar in Lebanon. (Psalms 92:12)</item>
<item>The LORD on high is mightier than the noise of many waters, yea, than the mighty waves of the sea. (Psalms 93:4)</item>
<item>He that worketh deceit shall not dwell within my house: he that telleth lies shall not tarry in my sight. (Psalms 101:7)</item>
<item>But the mercy of the LORD is from everlasting to everlasting upon them that fear him, and his righteousness unto children's children; (Psalms 103:17)</item>
<item>Thy word is a lamp unto my feet, and a light unto my path. (Psalms 119:105)</item>
<item>Behold, how good and how pleasant it is for brethren to dwell together in unity! (Psalms 133:1)</item>
<item>The LORD upholdeth all that fall, and raiseth up all those that be bowed down. (Psalms 145:14)</item>
<item>The LORD is nigh unto all them that call upon him, to all that call upon him in truth. (Psalms 145:18)</item>
<item>My son, if sinners entice thee, consent thou not. (Proverbs 1:10)</item>
<item>Let not mercy and truth forsake thee: bind them about thy neck; write them upon the table of thine heart: (Proverbs 3:3)</item>
<item>Trust in the LORD with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding. In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths. (Proverbs 3:5-6)</item>
<item>Wisdom is the principal thing; therefore get wisdom: and with all thy getting get understanding. (Proverbs 4:7)</item>
<item>But the path of the just is as the shining light, that shineth more and more unto the perfect day. (Proverbs 4:18)</item>
<item>Go to the ant, thou sluggard; consider her ways, and be wise: (Proverbs 6:6)</item>
<item>Can a man take fire in his bosom, and his clothes not be burned? Can one go upon hot coals, and his feet not be burned? (Proverbs 6:27-28)</item>
<item>For wisdom is better than rubies; and all the things that may be desired are not to be compared to it. (Proverbs 8:11)</item>
<item>Forsake the foolish, and live; and go in the way of understanding. (Proverbs 9:6)</item>
<item>The labour of the righteous tendeth to life: the fruit of the wicked to sin. (Proverbs 10:16)</item>
<item>A false balance is abomination to the LORD: but a just weight is his delight. (Proverbs 11:1)</item>
<item>When pride cometh, then cometh shame: but with the lowly is wisdom. (Proverbs 11:2)</item>
<item>The merciful man doeth good to his own soul: but he that is cruel troubleth his own flesh. (Proverbs 11:17)</item>
<item>Though hand join in hand, the wicked shall not be unpunished: but the seed of the righteous shall be delivered. (Proverbs 11:21)</item>
<item>The liberal soul shall be made fat: and he that watereth shall be watered also himself. (Proverbs 11:25)</item>
<item>He that trusteth in his riches shall fall; but the righteous shall flourish as a branch. (Proverbs 11:28)</item>
<item>A man shall be satisfied with good by the fruit of his mouth: and the recompence of a man's hands shall be rendered unto him. (Proverbs 12:14)</item>
<item>Lying lips are abomination to the LORD: but they that deal truly are his delight. (Proverbs 12:22)</item>
<item>The hand of the diligent shall bear rule: but the slothful shall be under tribute. (Proverbs 12:24)</item>
<item>Hope deferred maketh the heart sick: but when the desire cometh, it is a tree of life. (Proverbs 13:12)</item>
<item>He that walketh with wise men shall be wise: but a companion of fools shall be destroyed. (Proverbs 13:20)</item>
<item>He that spareth his rod hateth his son: but he that loveth him chasteneth him betimes. (Proverbs 13:24)</item>
<item>Fools make a mock at sin: but among the righteous there is favour. (Proverbs 14:9)</item>
<item>The heart knoweth his own bitterness; and a stranger doth not intermeddle with his joy. (Proverbs 14:10)</item>
<item>He that despiseth his neighbour sinneth: but he that hath mercy on the poor, happy is he. (Proverbs 14:21)</item>
<item>The wicked is driven away in his wickedness: but the righteous hath hope in his death. (Proverbs 14:32)</item>
<item>A soft answer turneth away wrath: but grievous words stir up anger. (Proverbs 15:1)</item>
<item>In the house of the righteous is much treasure: but in the revenues of the wicked is trouble. (Proverbs 15:6)</item>
<item>A merry heart maketh a cheerful countenance: but by sorrow of the heart the spirit is broken. (Proverbs 15:13)</item>
<item>Better is a dinner of herbs where love is, than a stalled ox and hatred therewith. (Proverbs 15:17)</item>
<item>A wise son maketh a glad father: but a foolish man despiseth his mother. (Proverbs 15:20)</item>
<item>A man hath joy by the answer of his mouth: and a word spoken in due season, how good is it! (Proverbs 15:23)</item>
<item>He that refuseth instruction despiseth his own soul: but he that heareth reproof getteth understanding. (Proverbs 15:32)</item>
<item>Commit thy works unto the LORD, and thy thoughts shall be established. (Proverbs 16:3)</item>
<item>When a man's ways please the LORD, he maketh even his enemies to be at peace with him. (Proverbs 16:7)</item>
<item>Pride goeth before destruction, and an haughty spirit before a fall. (Proverbs 16:18)</item>
<item>A froward man soweth strife: and a whisperer separateth chief friends. (Proverbs 16:28)</item>
<item>The hoary head is a crown of glory, if it be found in the way of righteousness. (Proverbs 16:31)</item>
<item>He that is slow to anger is better than the mighty; and he that ruleth his spirit than he that taketh a city. (Proverbs 16:32)</item>
<item>Whoso rewardeth evil for good, evil shall not depart from his house. (Proverbs 17:13)</item>
<item>A merry heart doeth good like a medicine: but a broken spirit drieth the bones. (Proverbs 17:22)</item>
<item>Wisdom is before him that hath understanding; but the eyes of a fool are in the ends of the earth. (Proverbs 17:24)</item>
<item>He that hath knowledge spareth his words: and a man of understanding is of an excellent spirit. (Proverbs 17:27)</item>
<item>Even a fool, when he holdeth his peace, is counted wise: and he that shutteth his lips is esteemed a man of understanding. (Proverbs 17:28)</item>
<item>Whoso findeth a wife findeth a good thing, and obtaineth favour of the LORD. (Proverbs 18:22)</item>
<item>Better is the poor that walketh in his integrity, than he that is perverse in his lips, and is a fool. (Proverbs 19:1)</item>
<item>Wealth maketh many friends; but the poor is separated from his neighbour. (Proverbs 19:4)</item>
<item>The discretion of a man deferreth his anger; and it is his glory to pass over a transgression. (Proverbs 19:11)</item>
<item>He that hath pity upon the poor lendeth unto the LORD; and that which he hath given will he pay him again. (Proverbs 19:17)</item>
<item>Wine is a mocker, strong drink is raging: and whosoever is deceived thereby is not wise. (Proverbs 20:1)</item>
<item>The sluggard will not plow by reason of the cold; therefore shall he beg in harvest, and have nothing. (Proverbs 20:4)</item>
<item>Even a child is known by his doings, whether his work be pure, and whether it be right. (Proverbs 20:11)</item>
<item>To do justice and judgment is more acceptable to the LORD than sacrifice. (Proverbs 21:3)</item>
<item>Whoso stoppeth his ears at the cry of the poor, he also shall cry himself, but shall not be heard. (Proverbs 21:13)</item>
<item>There is no wisdom nor understanding nor counsel against the LORD. (Proverbs 21:30)</item>
<item>A GOOD name is rather to be chosen than great riches, and loving favour rather than silver and gold. (Proverbs 22:1)</item>
<item>The rich and poor meet together: the LORD is the maker of them all. (Proverbs 22:2)</item>
<item>Train up a child in the way he should go: and when he is old, he will not depart from it. (Proverbs 22:6)</item>
<item>Foolishness is bound in the heart of a child; but the rod of correction shall drive it far from him. (Proverbs 22:15)</item>
<item>He that oppresseth the poor to increase his riches, and he that giveth to the rich, shall surely come to want. (Proverbs 22:16)</item>
<item>When thou sittest to eat with a ruler, consider diligently what is before thee: And put a knife to thy throat, if thou be a man given to appetite. (Proverbs 23:1-2)</item>
<item>Labour not to be rich: cease from thine own wisdom. (Proverbs 23:4)</item>
<item>Wilt thou set thine eyes upon that which is not? for riches certainly make themselves wings; they fly away as an eagle toward heaven. (Proverbs 23:5)</item>
<item>For as he thinketh in his heart, so is he: Eat and drink, saith he to thee; but his heart is not with thee. (Proverbs 23:7)</item>
<item>The father of the righteous shall greatly rejoice: and he that begetteth a wise child shall have joy of him. (Proverbs 23:24)</item>
<item>Be not thou envious against evil men, neither desire to be with them. (Proverbs 24:1)</item>
<item>For a just man falleth seven times, and riseth up again: but the wicked shall fall into mischief. (Proverbs 24:16)</item>
<item>Rejoice not when thine enemy falleth, and let not thine heart be glad when he stumbleth: (Proverbs 24:17)</item>
<item>Be not a witness against thy neighbour without cause; and deceive not with thy lips. (Proverbs 24:28)</item>
<item>Say not, I will do so to him as he hath done to me: I will render to the man according to his work. (Proverbs 24:29)</item>
<item>If thine enemy be hungry, give him bread to eat; and if he be thirsty, give him water to drink: For thou shalt heap coals of fire upon his head, and the LORD shall reward thee. (Proverbs 25:21-22)</item>
<item>Answer not a fool according to his folly, lest thou also be like unto him. (Proverbs 26:4)</item>
<item>Seest thou a man wise in his own conceit? there is more hope of a fool than of him. (Proverbs 26:12)</item>
<item>Where no wood is, there the fire goeth out: so where there is no talebearer, the strife ceaseth. (Proverbs 26:20)</item>
<item>Boast not thyself of to morrow; for thou knowest not what a day may bring forth. (Proverbs 27:1)</item>
<item>Faithful are the wounds of a friend; but the kisses of an enemy are deceitful. (Proverbs 27:6)</item>
<item>The wicked flee when no man pursueth: but the righteous are bold as a lion. (Proverbs 28:1)</item>
<item>He that covereth his sins shall not prosper: but whoso confesseth and forsaketh them shall have mercy. (Proverbs 28:13)</item>
<item>A faithful man shall abound with blessings: but he that maketh haste to be rich shall not be innocent. (Proverbs 28:20)</item>
<item>He that is of a proud heart stirreth up strife: but he that putteth his trust in the LORD shall be made fat. (Proverbs 28:25)</item>
<item>The rod and reproof give wisdom: but a child left to himself bringeth his mother to shame. (Proverbs 29:15)</item>
<item>She stretcheth out her hand to the poor; yea, she reacheth forth her hands to the needy. (Proverbs 31:20)</item>
<item>He that oppresseth the poor reproacheth his Maker: but he that honoureth him hath mercy on the poor. (Proverbs 144:31)</item>
<item>The thing that hath been, it is that which shall be; and that which is done is that which shall be done: and there is no new thing under the sun. (Ecclesiastes 1:9)</item>
<item>I have seen all the works that are done under the sun; and, behold, all is vanity and vexation of spirit. (Ecclesiastes 1:14)</item>
<item>To every thing there is a season, and a time to every purpose under the heaven: (Ecclesiastes 3:1)</item>
<item>I know that, whatsoever God doeth, it shall be for ever: nothing can be put to it, nor any thing taken from it: and God doeth it, that men should fear before him. (Ecclesiastes 3:14)</item>
<item>Be not rash with thy mouth, and let not thine heart be hasty to utter any thing before God: for God is in heaven, and thou upon earth: therefore let thy words be few. (Ecclesiastes 5:2)</item>
<item>He that loveth silver shall not be satisfied with silver; nor he that loveth abundance with increase: this is also vanity. (Ecclesiastes 5:10)</item>
<item>The sleep of a labouring man is sweet, whether he eat little or much: but the abundance of the rich will not suffer him to sleep. (Ecclesiastes 5:12)</item>
<item>A good name is better than precious ointment; and the day of death than the day of one's birth. (Ecclesiastes 7:1)</item>
<item>It is better to go to the house of mourning, than to go to the house of feasting: for that is the end of all men; and the living will lay it to his heart. (Ecclesiastes 7:2)</item>
<item>Sorrow is better than laughter: for by the sadness of the countenance the heart is made better. (Ecclesiastes 7:3)</item>
<item>It is better to hear the rebuke of the wise, than for a man to hear the song of fools. (Ecclesiastes 7:5)</item>
<item>Be not righteous over much; neither make thyself over wise: why shouldest thou destroy thyself ? (Ecclesiastes 7:16)</item>
<item>For to him that is joined to all the living there is hope: for a living dog is better than a dead lion. (Ecclesiastes 9:4)</item>
<item>Whatsoever thy hand findeth to do, do it with thy might; for there is no work, nor device, nor knowledge, nor wisdom, in the grave, whither thou goest. (Ecclesiastes 9:10)</item>
<item>I returned, and saw under the sun, that the race is not to the swift, nor the battle to the strong, neither yet bread to the wise, nor yet riches to men of understanding, nor yet favour to men of skill; but time and chance happeneth to them all. (Ecclesiastes 9:11)</item>
<item>Truly the light is sweet, and a pleasant thing it is for the eyes to behold the sun: But if a man live many years, and rejoice in them all; yet let him remember the days of darkness; for they shall be many. All that cometh is vanity. (Ecclesiastes 11:7-8)</item>
<item>Then shall the dust return to the earth as it was: and the spirit shall return unto God who gave it. (Ecclesiastes 12:7)</item>
<item>Woe unto them that rise up early in the morning, that they may follow strong drink; that continue until night, till wine inflame them! (Isaiah 5:11)</item>
<item>Woe unto them that call evil good, and good evil; that put darkness for light, and light for darkness; that put bitter for sweet, and sweet for bitter! (Isaiah 5:20)</item>
<item>Woe unto them that are wise in their own eyes, and prudent in their own sight! (Isaiah 5:21)</item>
<item>The wolf also shall dwell with the lamb, and the leopard shall lie down with the kid; and the calf and the young lion and the fatling together; and a little child shall lead them. (Isaiah 11:6)</item>
<item>Behold, God is my salvation; I will trust, and not be afraid: for the LORD JEHOVAH is my strength and my song; he also is become my salvation. (Isaiah 12:2)</item>
<item>And I will punish the world for their evil, and the wicked for their iniquity; and I will cause the arrogancy of the proud to cease, and will lay low the haughtiness of the terrible. (Isaiah 13:11)</item>
<item>And the work of righteousness shall be peace; and the effect of righteousness quietness and assurance for ever. (Isaiah 32:17)</item>
<item>Behold, the nations are as a drop of a bucket, and are counted as the small dust of the balance: behold, he taketh up the isles as a very little thing. (Isaiah 40:15)</item>
<item>Even the youths shall faint and be weary, and the young men shall utterly fall: But they that wait upon the LORD shall renew their strength; they shall mount up with wings as eagles; they shall run, and not be weary; and they shall walk, and not faint. (Isaiah 40:30-31)</item>
<item>Fear thou not; for I am with thee: be not dismayed; for I am thy God: I will strengthen thee; yea, I will help thee; yea, I will uphold thee with the right hand of my righteousness. (Isaiah 41:10)</item>
<item>No weapon that is formed against thee shall prosper; and every tongue that shall rise against thee in judgment thou shalt condemn. This is the heritage of the servants of the LORD, and their righteousness is of me, saith the LORD. (Isaiah 54:17)</item>
<item>Let the wicked forsake his way, and the unrighteous man his thoughts: and let him return unto the LORD, and he will have mercy upon him; and to our God, for he will abundantly pardon. (Isaiah 55:7)</item>
<item>For my thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, saith the LORD. For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts. (Isaiah 55:8-9)</item>
<item>Woe unto him that buildeth his house by unrighteousness, and his chambers by wrong; that useth his neighbour's service without wages, and giveth him not for his work; (Jeremiah 22:13)</item>
<item>The LORD is good unto them that wait for him, to the soul that seeketh him. (Lamentations 3:25)</item>
<item>It is good for a man that he bear the yoke in his youth. (Lamentations 3:27)</item>
<item>The soul that sinneth, it shall die. The son shall not bear the iniquity of the father, neither shall the father bear the iniquity of the son: the righteousness of the righteous shall be upon him, and the wickedness of the wicked shall be upon him. (Ezekiel 18:20)</item>
<item>He hath shewed thee, O man, what is good; and what doth the LORD require of thee, but to do justly, and to love mercy, and to walk humbly with thy God? (Micah 6:8)</item>
<item>Woe unto him that giveth his neighbour drink, that puttest thy bottle to him, and makest him drunken also, that thou mayest look on their nakedness! (Habakkuk 2:15)</item>
<item>These are the things that ye shall do; Speak ye every man the truth to his neighbour; execute the judgment of truth and peace in your gates: (Zechariah 8:16)</item>
<item>Have we not all one father? hath not one God created us? why do we deal treacherously every man against his brother, by profaning the covenant of our fathers? (Malachi 2:10)</item>
<item>But unto you that fear my name shall the Sun of righteousness arise with healing in his wings; and ye shall go forth, and grow up as calves of the stall. (Malachi 4:2)</item>
<item>...Man shall not live by bread alone, but by every word that proceedeth out of the mouth of God. (Matthew 4:4)</item>
<item>Blessed are the poor in spirit: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven. (Matthew 5:3)</item>
<item>Blessed are they that mourn: for they shall be comforted. (Matthew 5:4)</item>
<item>Blessed are the meek: for they shall inherit the earth. (Matthew 5:5)</item>
<item>Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness: for they shall be filled. (Matthew 5:6)</item>
<item>Blessed are the merciful: for they shall obtain mercy. (Matthew 5:7)</item>
<item>Blessed are the pure in heart: for they shall see God. (Matthew 5:8)</item>
<item>Blessed are the peacemakers: for they shall be called the children of God. (Matthew 5:9)</item>
<item>Ye are the salt of the earth: but if the salt have lost his savour, wherewith shall it be salted? it is thenceforth good for nothing, but to be cast out, and to be trodden under foot of men. (Matthew 5:13)</item>
<item>Ye are the light of the world. A city that is set on an hill cannot be hid. (Matthew 5:14)</item>
<item>Ye have heard that it was said by them of old time, Thou shalt not commit adultery: But I say unto you, That whosoever looketh on a woman to lust after her hath committed adultery with her already in his heart. (Matthew 5:27-28)</item>
<item>Ye have heard that it hath been said, An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a tooth: But I say unto you, That ye resist not evil: but whosoever shall smite thee on thy right cheek, turn to him the other also. (Matthew 5:38-39)</item>
<item>Give to him that asketh thee, and from him that would borrow of thee turn not thou away. (Matthew 5:42)</item>
<item>Ye have heard that it hath been said, Thou shalt love thy neighbour, and hate thine enemy. But I say unto you, Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them which despitefully use you, and persecute you; (Matthew 5:43-44)</item>
<item>But when thou doest alms, let not thy left hand know what thy right hand doeth: (Matthew 6:3)</item>
<item>But when ye pray, use not vain repetitions, as the heathen do: for they think that they shall be heard for their much speaking. (Matthew 6:7)</item>
<item>For if ye forgive men their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you: (Matthew 6:14)</item>
<item>Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon earth, where moth and rust doth corrupt, and where thieves break through and steal: But lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven, where neither moth nor rust doth corrupt, and where thieves do not break through nor steal: (Matthew 6:19-20)</item>
<item>For where your treasure is, there will your heart be also. (Matthew 6:21)</item>
<item>No man can serve two masters: for either he will hate the one, and love the other; or else he will hold to the one, and despise the other. Ye cannot serve God and mammon. (Matthew 6:24)</item>
<item>Therefore I say unto you, Take no thought for your life, what ye shall eat, or what ye shall drink; nor yet for your body, what ye shall put on. Is not the life more than meat, and the body than raiment? Behold the fowls of the air: for they sow not, neither do they reap, nor gather into barns; yet your heavenly Father feedeth them. Are ye not much better than they? (Matthew 6:25-26)</item>
<item>But seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness; and all these things shall be added unto you. (Matthew 6:33)</item>
<item>Take therefore no thought for the morrow: for the morrow shall take thought for the things of itself. Sufficient unto the day is the evil thereof. (Matthew 6:34)</item>
<item>Judge not, that ye be not judged. (Matthew 7:1)</item>
<item>Give not that which is holy unto the dogs, neither cast ye your pearls before swine, lest they trample them under their feet, and turn again and rend you. (Matthew 7:6)</item>
<item>Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you: (Matthew 7:7)</item>
<item>Therefore all things whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them: for this is the law and the prophets. (Matthew 7:12)</item>
<item>Neither do men put new wine into old bottles: else the bottles break, and the wine runneth out, and the bottles perish: but they put new wine into new bottles, and both are preserved. (Matthew 9:17)</item>
<item>Behold, I send you forth as sheep in the midst of wolves: be ye therefore wise as serpents, and harmless as doves. (Matthew 10:16)</item>
<item>And ye shall be hated of all men for my name's sake: but he that endureth to the end shall be saved. (Matthew 10:22)</item>
<item>And fear not them which kill the body, but are not able to kill the soul: but rather fear him which is able to destroy both soul and body in hell. (Matthew 10:28)</item>
<item>Whosoever therefore shall confess me before men, him will I confess also before my Father which is in heaven. But whosoever shall deny me before men, him will I also deny before my Father which is in heaven. (Matthew 10:32-33)</item>
<item>Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. Take my yoke upon you, and learn of me; for I am meek and lowly in heart: and ye shall find rest unto your souls. For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light. (Matthew 11:28-30)</item>
<item>Either make the tree good, and his fruit good; or else make the tree corrupt, and his fruit corrupt: for the tree is known by his fruit. (Matthew 12:33)</item>
<item>...And if the blind lead the blind, both shall fall into the ditch. (Matthew 15:14)</item>
<item>But he turned, and said unto Peter, Get thee behind me, Satan: thou art an offence unto me: for thou savourest not the things that be of God, but those that be of men. (Matthew 16:23)</item>
<item>And Jesus said unto them, Because of your unbelief: for verily I say unto you, If ye have faith as a grain of mustard seed, ye shall say unto this mountain, Remove hence to yonder place; and it shall remove; and nothing shall be impossible unto you. (Matthew 17:20)</item>
<item>Again I say unto you, That if two of you shall agree on earth as touching any thing that they shall ask, it shall be done for them of my Father which is in heaven. (Matthew 18:19)</item>
<item>And I say unto you, Whosoever shall put away his wife, except it be for fornication, and shall marry another, committeth adultery: and whoso marrieth her which is put away doth commit adultery. (Matthew 19:9)</item>
<item>But Jesus beheld them, and said unto them, With men this is impossible; but with God all things are possible. (Matthew 19:26)</item>
<item>For many are called, but few are chosen. (Matthew 22:14)</item>
<item>They say unto him, Caesar's. Then saith he unto them, Render therefore unto Caesar the things which are Caesar's; and unto God the things that are God's. (Matthew 22:21)</item>
<item>Jesus said unto him, Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. This is the first and great commandment.And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself. On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets. (Matthew 22:37-40)</item>
<item>And call no man your father upon the earth: for one is your Father, which is in heaven. (Matthew 23:9)</item>
<item>For this is my blood of the new testament, which is shed for many for the remission of sins. (Matthew 26:28)</item>
<item>Watch and pray, that ye enter not into temptation: the spirit indeed is willing, but the flesh is weak. (Matthew 26:41)</item>
<item>Then said Jesus unto him, Put up again thy sword into his place: for all they that take the sword shall perish with the sword. (Matthew 26:52)</item>
<item>And he said unto them, The sabbath was made for man, and not man for the sabbath: Therefore the Son of man is Lord also of the sabbath. (Mark 2:27-28)</item>
<item>And if a house be divided against itself, that house cannot stand. (Mark 3:25)</item>
<item>And he said unto them, He that hath ears to hear, let him hear. (Mark 4:9)</item>
<item>For what shall it profit a man, if he shall gain the whole world, and lose his own soul? (Mark 8:36)</item>
<item>Jesus said unto him, If thou canst believe, all things are possible to him that believeth. (Mark 9:23)</item>
<item>And he sat down, and called the twelve, and saith unto them, If any man desire to be first, the same shall be last of all, and servant of all. (Mark 9:35)</item>
<item>And if thy hand offend thee, cut it off: it is better for thee to enter into life maimed, than having two hands to go into hell, into the fire that never shall be quenched: (Mark 9:43)</item>
<item>What therefore God hath joined together, let not man put asunder. (Mark 10:9)</item>
<item>But when Jesus saw it, he was much displeased, and said unto them, Suffer the little children to come unto me, and forbid them not: for of such is the kingdom of God. (Mark 10:14)</item>
<item>Verily I say unto you, Whosoever shall not receive the kingdom of God as a little child, he shall not enter therein. (Mark 10:15)</item>
<item>And when ye stand praying, forgive, if ye have ought against any: that your Father also which is in heaven may forgive you your trespasses. (Mark 11:25)</item>
<item>For with God nothing shall be impossible. (Luke 1:37)</item>
<item>And Jesus answered and said unto him, Get thee behind me, Satan: for it is written, Thou shalt worship the Lord thy God, and him only shalt thou serve. (Luke 4:8)</item>
<item>And as ye would that men should do to you, do ye also to them likewise. (Luke 6:31)</item>
<item>But love ye your enemies, and do good, and lend, hoping for nothing again; and your reward shall be great, and ye shall be the children of the Highest: for he is kind unto the unthankful and to the evil. (Luke 6:35)</item>
<item>Give, and it shall be given unto you; good measure, pressed down, and shaken together, and running over, shall men give into your bosom. For with the same measure that ye mete withal it shall be measured to you again. (Luke 6:38)</item>
<item>And he said unto them, Take heed, and beware of covetousness: for a man's life consisteth not in the abundance of the things which he possesseth. (Luke 12:15)</item>
<item>I say unto you, that likewise joy shall be in heaven over one sinner that repenteth, more than over ninety and nine just persons, which need no repentance. (Luke 15:7)</item>
<item>Take heed to yourselves: If thy brother trespass against thee, rebuke him; and if he repent, forgive him. (Luke 17:3)</item>
<item>And the apostles said unto the Lord, Increase our faith. And the Lord said, If ye had faith as a grain of mustard seed, ye might say unto this sycamine tree, Be thou plucked up by the root, and be thou planted in the sea; and it should obey you. (Luke 17:5-6)</item>
<item>For it is easier for a camel to go through a needle's eye, than for a rich man to enter into the kingdom of God. (Luke 18:25)</item>
<item>In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. (John 1:1)</item>
<item>The next day John seeth Jesus coming unto him, and saith, Behold the Lamb of God, which taketh away the sin of the world. (John 1:29)</item>
<item>Jesus answered and said unto him, Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born again, he cannot see the kingdom of God. (John 3:3)</item>
<item>The wind bloweth where it listeth, and thou hearest the sound thereof, but canst not tell whence it cometh, and whither it goeth: so is every one that is born of the Spirit. (John 3:8)</item>
<item>For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life. (John 3:16)</item>
<item>God is a Spirit: and they that worship him must worship him in spirit and in truth. (John 4:24)</item>
<item>Verily, verily, I say unto you, He that heareth my word, and believeth on him that sent me, hath everlasting life, and shall not come into condemnation; but is passed from death unto life. (John 5:24)</item>
<item>And this is the will of him that sent me, that every one which seeth the Son, and believeth on him, may have everlasting life: and I will raise him up at the last day. (John 6:40)</item>
<item>Judge not according to the appearance, but judge righteous judgment. (John 7:24)</item>
<item>Then spake Jesus again unto them, saying, I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life. (John 8:12)</item>
<item>Then said Jesus to those Jews which believed on him, If ye continue in my word, then are ye my disciples indeed; And ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free. (John 8:31-32)</item>
<item>Jesus said unto her, I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live: And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die. Believest thou this? (John 11:25-26)</item>
<item>Jesus saith unto him, I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me. (John 14:6)</item>
<item>I am the vine, ye are the branches: He that abideth in me, and I in him, the same bringeth forth much fruit: for without me ye can do nothing. (John 15:5)</item>
<item>Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends. (John 15:13)</item>
<item>If the world hate you, ye know that it hated me before it hated you. (John 15:18)</item>
<item>Then Peter said unto them, Repent, and be baptized every one of you in the name of Jesus Christ for the remission of sins, and ye shall receive the gift of the Holy Ghost. (Acts 2:38)</item>
<item>...It is more blessed to give than to receive. (Acts 20:35)</item>
<item>But God commendeth his love toward us, in that, while we were yet sinners, Christ died for us. Much more then, being now justified by his blood, we shall be saved from wrath through him. (Romans 5:8-9)</item>
<item>For the wages of sin is death; but the gift of God is eternal life through Jesus Christ our Lord. (Romans 6:23)</item>
<item>And we know that all things work together for good to them that love God, to them who are the called according to his purpose. (Romans 8:28)</item>
<item>For whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved. (Romans 10:13)</item>
<item>So we, being many, are one body in Christ, and every one members one of another. (Romans 12:5)</item>
<item>Be of the same mind one toward another. Mind not high things, but condescend to men of low estate. Be not wise in your own conceits. (Romans 12:16)</item>
<item>Therefore if thine enemy hunger, feed him; if he thirst, give him drink: for in so doing thou shalt heap coals of fire on his head. (Romans 12:20)</item>
<item>Be not overcome of evil, but overcome evil with good. (Romans 12:21)</item>
<item>Let every soul be subject unto the higher powers. For there is no power but of God: the powers that be are ordained of God. (Romans 13:1)</item>
<item>Render therefore to all their dues: tribute to whom tribute is due; custom to whom custom; fear to whom fear; honour to whom honour. (Romans 13:7)</item>
<item>Love worketh no ill to his neighbour: therefore love is the fulfilling of the law. (Romans 13:10)</item>
<item>And he that doubteth is damned if he eat, because he eateth not of faith: for whatsoever is not of faith is sin. (Romans 14:23)</item>
<item>For whatsoever things were written aforetime were written for our learning, that we through patience and comfort of the scriptures might have hope. (Romans 15:4)</item>
<item>Wherefore receive ye one another, as Christ also received us to the glory of God. (Romans 15:7)</item>
<item>I have planted, Apollos watered; but God gave the increase. (1 Corinthians 3:6)</item>
<item>Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and that the Spirit of God dwelleth in you? (1 Corinthians 3:16)</item>
<item>Wherefore let him that thinketh he standeth take heed lest he fall. (1 Corinthians 10:12)</item>
<item>There hath no temptation taken you but such as is common to man: but God is faithful, who will not suffer you to be tempted above that ye are able; but will with the temptation also make a way to escape, that ye may be able to bear it. (1 Corinthians 10:13)</item>
<item>Whether therefore ye eat, or drink, or whatsoever ye do, do all to the glory of God. (1 Corinthians 10:31)</item>
<item>Charity suffereth long, and is kind; charity envieth not; charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up, Doth not behave itself unseemly, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil; Rejoiceth not in iniquity, but rejoiceth in the truth; Beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things. (1 Corinthians 13:4-7)</item>
<item>When I was a child, I spake as a child, I understood as a child, I thought as a child: but when I became a man, I put away childish things. (1 Corinthians 13:11)</item>
<item>And now abideth faith, hope, charity, these three; but the greatest of these is charity. (1 Corinthians 13:13)</item>
<item>Be not deceived: evil communications corrupt good manners. (1 Corinthians 15:33)</item>
<item>...We walk by faith, not by sight. (2 Corinthians 5:7)</item>
<item>Be ye not unequally yoked together with unbelievers: for what fellowship hath righteousness with unrighteousness? and what communion hath light with darkness? (2 Corinthians 6:14)</item>
<item>And God is able to make all grace abound toward you; that ye, always having all sufficiency in all things, may abound to every good work: (2 Corinthians 9:8)</item>
<item>Now the works of the flesh are manifest, which are these; Adultery, fornication, uncleanness, lasciviousness, Idolatry, witchcraft, hatred, variance, emulations, wrath, strife, seditions, heresies, Envyings, murders, drunkenness, revellings, and such like: of the which I tell you before, as I have also told you in time past, that they which do such things shall not herit the kingdom of God. (Galatians 5:19-21)</item>
<item>But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness, goodness, faith, Meekness, temperance: against such there is no law. (Galatians 5:22-23)</item>
<item>Bear ye one another's burdens, and so fulfil the law of Christ. (Galatians 6:2)</item>
<item>For every man shall bear his own burden. (Galatians 6:5)</item>
<item>Be not deceived; God is not mocked: for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap. (Galatians 6:7)</item>
<item>And let us not be weary in well doing: for in due season we shall reap, if we faint not. (Galatians 6:9)</item>
<item>As we have therefore opportunity, let us do good unto all men, especially unto them who are of the household of faith. (Galatians 6:10)</item>
<item>For by grace are ye saved through faith; and that not of yourselves: it is the gift of God: Not of works, lest any man should boast. (Ephesians 2:8-9)</item>
<item>For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus unto good works, which God hath before ordained that we should walk in them. (Ephesians 2:10)</item>
<item>Be ye angry, and sin not: let not the sun go down upon your wrath: (Ephesians 4:26)</item>
<item>Let no man deceive you with vain words: for because of these things cometh the wrath of God upon the children of disobedience. (Ephesians 5:6)</item>
<item>And be not drunk with wine, wherein is excess; but be filled with the Spirit; (Ephesians 5:18)</item>
<item>Let nothing be done through strife or vainglory; but in lowliness of mind let each esteem other better than themselves. (Philippians 2:3)</item>
<item>And the peace of God, which passeth all understanding, shall keep your hearts and minds through Christ Jesus. (Philippians 4:7)</item>
<item>As ye have therefore received Christ Jesus the Lord, so walk ye in him: (Colossians 2:6)</item>
<item>Beware lest any man spoil you through philosophy and vain deceit, after the tradition of men, after the rudiments of the world, and not after Christ. (Colossians 2:8)</item>
<item>Forbearing one another, and forgiving one another, if any man have a quarrel against any: even as Christ forgave you, so also do ye. (Colossians 3:13)</item>
<item>And whatsoever ye do in word or deed, do all in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God and the Father by him. (Colossians 3:17)</item>
<item>And whatsoever ye do, do it heartily, as to the Lord, and not unto men; (Colossians 3:23)</item>
<item>Let your speech be alway with grace, seasoned with salt, that ye may know how ye ought to answer every man. (Colossians 4:6)</item>
<item>And the Lord make you to increase and abound in love one toward another, and toward all men, even as we do toward you: (1 Thessalonians 3:12)</item>
<item>Now we exhort you, brethren, warn them that are unruly, comfort the feebleminded, support the weak, be patient toward all men. (1 Thessalonians 5:14)</item>
<item>Rejoice evermore. Pray without ceasing. In every thing give thanks: for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus concerning you. (1 Thessalonians 5:16-18)</item>
<item>But we know that the law is good, if a man use it lawfully; Knowing this, that the law is not made for a righteous man, but for the lawless and disobedient, for the ungodly and for sinners, for unholy and profane, for murderers of fathers and murderers of mothers, for manslayers. (1 Timothy 1:8-9)</item>
<item>For the scripture saith, Thou shalt not muzzle the ox that treadeth out the corn. And, The labourer is worthy of his reward. (1 Timothy 5:18)</item>
<item>For we brought nothing into this world, and it is certain we can carry nothing out. (1 Timothy 6:7)</item>
<item>For the love of money is the root of all evil: which while some coveted after, they have erred from the faith, and pierced themselves through with many sorrows. (1 Timothy 6:10)</item>
<item>O Timothy, keep that which is committed to thy trust, avoiding profane and vain babblings, and oppositions of science falsely so called: Which some professing have erred concerning the faith. Grace be with thee. Amen. (1 Timothy 6:20-21)</item>
<item>Hold fast the form of sound words, which thou hast heard of me, in faith and love which is in Christ Jesus. (2 Timothy 1:13)</item>
<item>Study to shew thyself approved unto God, a workman that needeth not to be ashamed, rightly dividing the word of truth. But shun profane and vain babblings: for they will increase unto more ungodliness. (2 Timothy 2:15-16)</item>
<item>I have fought a good fight, I have finished my course, I have kept the faith: (2 Timothy 4:7)</item>
<item>Unto the pure all things are pure: but unto them that are defiled and unbelieving is nothing pure; but even their mind and conscience is defiled. (Titus 1:15)</item>
<item>Now faith is the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen. (Hebrews 11:1)</item>
<item>But without faith it is impossible to please him: for he that cometh to God must believe that he is, and that he is a rewarder of them that diligently seek him. (Hebrews 11:6)</item>
<item>...My son, despise not thou the chastening of the Lord, nor faint when thou art rebuked of him: For whom the Lord loveth he chasteneth, and scourgeth every son whom he receiveth. (Hebrews 12:5-6)</item>
<item>Be not forgetful to entertain strangers: for thereby some have entertained angels unawares. (Hebrews 13:2)</item>
<item>Marriage is honourable in all, and the bed undefiled: but whoremongers and adulterers God will judge. (Hebrews 13:4)</item>
<item>Jesus Christ the same yesterday, and to day, and for ever. (Hebrews 13:8)</item>
<item>If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him. (James 1:5)</item>
<item>Blessed is the man that endureth temptation: for when he is tried, he shall receive the crown of life, which the Lord hath promised to them that love him. (James 1:12)</item>
<item>Wherefore, my beloved brethren, let every man be swift to hear, slow to speak, slow to wrath: For the wrath of man worketh not the righteousness of God. (James 1:19-20)</item>
<item>If any man among you seem to be religious, and bridleth not his tongue, but deceiveth his own heart, this man's religion is vain. (James 1:26)</item>
<item>For he shall have judgment without mercy, that hath shewed no mercy; and mercy rejoiceth against judgment. (James 2:13)</item>
<item>For every kind of beasts, and of birds, and of serpents, and of things in the sea, is tamed, and hath been tamed of mankind: But the tongue can no man tame; it is an unruly evil, full of deadly poison. (James 3:7-8)</item>
<item>For where envying and strife is, there is confusion and every evil work. (James 3:16)</item>
<item>Submit yourselves therefore to God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you. (James 4:7)</item>
<item>Is any among you afflicted? let him pray. Is any merry? let him sing psalms. (James 5:13)</item>
<item>Confess your faults one to another, and pray one for another, that ye may be healed. The effectual fervent prayer of a righteous man availeth much. (James 5:16)</item>
<item>Honour all men. Love the brotherhood. Fear God. Honour the king. (1 Peter 2:17)</item>
<item>Who his own self bare our sins in his own body on the tree, that we, being dead to sins, should live unto righteousness: by whose stripes ye were healed. (1 Peter 2:24)</item>
<item>Finally, be ye all of one mind, having compassion one of another, love as brethren, be pitiful, be courteous: Not rendering evil for evil, or railing for railing: but contrariwise blessing; knowing that ye are thereunto called, that ye should inherit a blessing. (1 Peter 3:8-9)</item>
<item>For he that will love life, and see good days, let him refrain his tongue from evil, and his lips that they speak no guile: (1 Peter 3:10)</item>
<item>And above all things have fervent charity among yourselves: for charity shall cover the multitude of sins. (1 Peter 4:8)</item>
<item>Use hospitality one to another without grudging. (1 Peter 4:9)</item>
<item>Humble yourselves therefore under the mighty hand of God, that he may exalt you in due time: Casting all your care upon him; for he careth for you. (1 Peter 5:6-7)</item>
<item>Be sober, be vigilant; because your adversary the devil, as a roaring lion, walketh about, seeking whom he may devour: (1 Peter 5:8)</item>
<item>We have also a more sure word of prophecy; whereunto ye do well that ye take heed, as unto a light that shineth in a dark place, until the day dawn, and the day star arise in your hearts: Knowing this first, that no prophecy of the scripture is of any private interpretation. (2 Peter 1:19-20)</item>
<item>The Lord is not slack concerning his promise, as some men count slackness; but is longsuffering to us-ward, not willing that any should perish, but that all should come to repentance. (2 Peter 3:9)</item>
<item>But the day of the Lord will come as a thief in the night; in the which the heavens shall pass away with a great noise, and the elements shall melt with fervent heat, the earth also and the works that are therein shall be burned up. (2 Peter 3:10)</item>
<item>If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins, and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness. (1 John 1:9)</item>
<item>He that saith he is in the light, and hateth his brother, is in darkness even until now. (1 John 2:9)</item>
<item>Love not the world, neither the things that are in the world. If any man love the world, the love of the Father is not in him. (1 John 2:15)</item>
<item>Whosoever hateth his brother is a murderer: and ye know that no murderer hath eternal life abiding in him. (1 John 3:15)</item>
<item>But whoso hath this world's good, and seeth his brother have need, and shutteth up his bowels of compassion from him, how dwelleth the love of God in him? (1 John 3:17)</item>
<item>There is no fear in love; but perfect love casteth out fear: because fear hath torment. He that feareth is not made perfect in love. (1 John 4:1)</item>
<item>And God shall wipe away all tears from their eyes; and there shall be no more death, neither sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there be any more pain: for the former things are passed away. (Revelation 21:4)</item>
<item>And he said unto me, It is done. I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end. I will give unto him that is athirst of the fountain of the water of life freely. (Revelation 21:6)</item>
<item>I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end, the first and the last. (Revelation 22:13)</item>
</array>

</resources>
